<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Food-for-Thought on knowledge base</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/food-for-thought/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Food-for-Thought on knowledge base</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2021 21:36:49 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/food-for-thought/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dangerous Man Are Virtuous</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2120d4dc2552df1cb649e931019142d0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2021 21:36:49 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2120d4dc2552df1cb649e931019142d0/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You shouldn&amp;rsquo;t harm anyone, which it right. One should not. To add-in man should be harmless either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should be dangerous and monstrous but in civilised manner. All the human we look up to aren&amp;rsquo;t harmless. Shri Ram is great archer and capable to defeating whole kingdom. Shri krishna said to have single handedly changed course of mahabharata.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have all heard stories of third eye of shiva. His ange can bring havoc. The message is harmless men are not virtuous. It&amp;rsquo;s the dangerous man under control that are virtuous and human to look upto.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Money to Buy Time</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/3f0f98b1a3c3258c2a2f705d58bb3595/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 23:33:57 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/3f0f98b1a3c3258c2a2f705d58bb3595/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you have enough to get basic life go by(for needs not for greed), extra money should be used to buy time. Initially you need t sell your time to make money, once there, basic needs taken care of start using money to buy time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tweet was inspired was&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take every opportunity you get to use money to buy time, and then proceed to “waste” that extra time in doing things that cannot be bought for money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are few things money can&amp;rsquo;t buy for me like health, family, friendship, trust etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply enjoy life to fullest to whatever be your defination. Money if very important part of life, but shouldn&amp;rsquo;t become life. Life is much more than that.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ankurwarikoo 41 Things at 41</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/1e0b24f24f6a5963366cc66d84ad098f/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2021 16:56:43 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/1e0b24f24f6a5963366cc66d84ad098f/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Read it somewhere, you can&amp;rsquo;t make mistakes. You&amp;rsquo;ve to learn from others&amp;rsquo; mistakes/experiences. Read this post from &lt;a href=&#34;https://ankurwarikoo.com/contact/&#34;&gt;ankur warikoo&lt;/a&gt;, so thought of writing about it, to internalize it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Funny one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The only success for a company is when it raises money from customers. Congratulations when raising from money from founder is like, congratulating chef on buying vegetables&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Useful&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you share your failure openly, you instantly take away all the power    that the world had over you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s similar to 8 mile &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xh1ROLEDyP4&amp;t=170s&#34;&gt;last rap battle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Managing your time is about managing your energy, managing your energy is about managing your attention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For me also, it is all about your focus and this is especially relevant in time where there are all fun and good youtube videos around to take your time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take criticism seriously but not personally&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This has been my journey, has been detached from surroundings but still not taking unwarranted criticism(which you don&amp;rsquo;t agree to) personally should be part of my journey. Understanding it&amp;rsquo;s their opinion and still choice is with me how I take it up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Also need to internalise response vs react. Always respond not react. You should not give anyone power over you, on how you response, that should only be yours and yours only.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;World doesn&amp;rsquo;t need one more template, world need one more rebel&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a good food for thought #food-for-thought&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Never complain&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remember this, have learnt it the hard way. Whatever it is, just don&amp;rsquo;t complain. It would never fix things, just aggravate them. Learn to handle them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The decision that will hurt you the most is not making one while waiting to take the right one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FOr waiting for the right time, has hurt more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayes Rule and Medical Tests</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/bookmarks/bayes-rule-medical-tests/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 08:54:42 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/bookmarks/bayes-rule-medical-tests/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;All medical tests do is update their probability of having disease, and not tell if we have disease or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are three things&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prevalence  : How common is that disease around here? What chance of having it without tests?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sensitivity : If even disease is present, how good is the test at detecting it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Specificity : If a test is taken, there can be other issues that result. Clots in the pancreas can be because of a lot many things. How specific is test for that specific disease.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example which he told&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prevalence : 1%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sensitivity : 90%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Specificity : 91%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;So even if you haven&amp;rsquo;t taken test, there is &lt;strong&gt;1%&lt;/strong&gt; chance of you having that disease. So taking a test based on the test&amp;rsquo;s Sensitivity and Specificity would increase and decrease that probability.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To calculate your probability faster is to get the Bayes factor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;lntable&#34;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;1
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;2
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;Bayes factor = Sensitivity / False positive
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;Bayes factor =  (Probability of having cancer after test is positive) / (Probability of not having cancer after test is positive)
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bayes factor is also called likelihood ratio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For above values :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Probability of having cancer after test is positive : 90 in 100 (90%)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Probability of test is false positive (100 - specificity) i.e 9&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;So likelihood ratio is : 90 / 0 i.e. 10&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So in the first case without test, there was 1% i.e. 1 in 100 that you&amp;rsquo;ve cancer without test. After the test, your chances just get updated. After test is positive your chances are:  1/100 * 10 ~ 1/10. So that is also not 100% sure now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So for tests your symptoms, contacts, genetics all come up to increase the chance, but still not 100%, we need to remember. &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;All tests do is update the chances of having it, but not sure shot thing. Until tests are bulletproof.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;better-to-watch-the-whole-video-above-are-just-notes-taken-from-there&#34;&gt;Better to watch the whole video, above are just notes taken from there.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of top comments for youtube channel&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a doctor I&amp;rsquo;m so happy you&amp;rsquo;re using your platform to get this information out. Let me tell you though&amp;hellip; it gets way more complicated! Unfortunately prevalence estimates aren&amp;rsquo;t always known and are constantly changing (especially in pandemics). Another thing to consider is the gold standard. If your test looks for breast cancer you can cut out the lump and look at it under a microscope. Some diseases aren&amp;rsquo;t as easily clarified. For instance, since we don&amp;rsquo;t have a highly accurate, easy test for pancreatic cancer we rely on imaging, demographics, blood markers, symptoms (or lack thereof) as multiple things that form a conglomerate test to increase our Bayes factor. Despite all these things we can&amp;rsquo;t always get a great prediction on whether that scar in your bile duct is cancer or just a residual scar from pancreatitis you had 10 years ago. So we offer the patient a huge surgery to remove the head of their pancreas and duodenum only to find that it wasn&amp;rsquo;t cancer. You can imagine the patient is happy it&amp;rsquo;s not cancer but not so happy they don&amp;rsquo;t have half their pancreas and have abdominal pain and maybe diabetes. Medicine is a tricky thing. Another tricky thing is operator error. Some tests depend on the skill of the lab tech, radiologist, or surgeon. The complexity of the human body and the uniqueness of each individual also plays a role. Your test may be false positive in a particular patient 100% of the time because they have some strange protein mutation. It&amp;rsquo;s tough!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is Not Love</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/bookmarks/what-is-not-love/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 10:12:30 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/bookmarks/what-is-not-love/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This youtube video(click the title, that is how bookmarks are arranged for all posts), is of Abraham Joshua Heshel Twerski, an Israeli-American Hasidic rabbi, a scion of the Chernobyl Hasidic dynasty, and a psychiatrist specializing in substance abuse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;External-love is what I&amp;rsquo;m going to give, not what I&amp;rsquo;m going to get. (This line is bit vague)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I good line that i need to keep in check is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;People make serious mistake in thinking, that you give to those who you love, and the answer is  you love to those whom you give&amp;rdquo;
His point is, if I give something to you, I have invested myself in you, since self-love is given everybody loves themselves, now that part of me has become in you, there is part of me in you that I love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing that i read long back was:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want someone to be open to you, go ask for some favour, once people have done favor they are more open to talk to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not sure if above is good advice, never understood it properly, so please try at your own risk, but that goes by the same theory mentioned in first quote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not in alignment with his ideas, sounds good though. Got similar thoughts with brahma kumaris(&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7dNPNtdaMWY&amp;list=PLCE9046E85D3918D8)&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7dNPNtdaMWY&amp;list=PLCE9046E85D3918D8)&lt;/a&gt;, still not in agreement with it. Love if feeling(people say), which I don&amp;rsquo;t understand and not sure what this work exactly mean. Care I understand, responsibility I comprehend, but not sure of Love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reference:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Abraham_J._Twerski&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Abraham_J._Twerski&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>People Do Not Care</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/bookmarks/people-do-not-care/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 12:22:20 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/bookmarks/people-do-not-care/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You get up every morning.&lt;br&gt;
You show up.&lt;br&gt;
You do the right things.&lt;br&gt;
You work really really hard.&lt;br&gt;
Don’t cheat, don’t steal, don’t beg, don’t lie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the honest truth – People don’t care!&lt;br&gt;
People don’t care if you are doing the right thing.&lt;br&gt;
They only care if you are doing the right thing for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;tldr : If they care they care, if they don&amp;rsquo;t they don&amp;rsquo;t and that shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be once concern.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Truely, it makes sense people would only care if you do right thing for them&lt;/strong&gt;, but that shouldn&amp;rsquo;t concern us. It is not in our control, so why worry in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reason for doing sometime should be because &lt;strong&gt;you care&lt;/strong&gt; not because someone else does. Personally learnt it hard way that people pleasing or doing because someone else wants/cares is stupid idea. For me personally, it was because I had low self-respect for myself.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video: A glimpse into ancient indian astronomy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/bookmarks/video-a-glimpse-into-ancient-indian-astronomy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2020 20:18:01 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/bookmarks/video-a-glimpse-into-ancient-indian-astronomy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Astrology has always intrigued me, specifically indian style of astrology, have heard a lot about it. Lunar calendar and rituals and traditions around it always facinate me a lot. I have some longing for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Haven&amp;rsquo;t worked on it much, but this video again brings those question back to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Path for me is language first, will have to learn sanskrit first, then i would have lot of venues open to me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Federation Is Worst of All Worlds</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/bookmarks/federation-is-worst-of-all-worlds/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 04:13:47 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/bookmarks/federation-is-worst-of-all-worlds/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>

