<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>food-for-thought on knowledge base</title>
    <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/tags/food-for-thought/</link>
    <description>Recent content in food-for-thought on knowledge base</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 23:33:57 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kbs.murarisumit.in/tags/food-for-thought/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Use Money to Buy Time</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/3f0f98b1a3c3258c2a2f705d58bb3595/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 23:33:57 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/3f0f98b1a3c3258c2a2f705d58bb3595/</guid>
      <description>If you have enough to get basic life go by(for needs not for greed), extra money should be used to buy time. Initially you need t sell your time to make money, once there, basic needs taken care of start using money to buy time.
Tweet was inspired was
 Take every opportunity you get to use money to buy time, and then proceed to “waste” that extra time in doing things that cannot be bought for money.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ankurwarikoo 41 Things at 41</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/1e0b24f24f6a5963366cc66d84ad098f/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2021 16:56:43 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/1e0b24f24f6a5963366cc66d84ad098f/</guid>
      <description>He turned 41 last week. Here are 41 reflections about his life, which he remain immensely grateful for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayes Rule and Medical Tests</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/bayes-rule-medical-tests/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 08:54:42 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/bayes-rule-medical-tests/</guid>
      <description>All medical tests do is update their probability of having disease, and not tell if we have disease or not.
There are three things
 Prevalence : How common is that disease around here? What chance of having it without tests? Sensitivity : If even disease is present, how good is the test at detecting it. Specificity : If a test is taken, there can be other issues that result. Clots in the pancreas can be because of a lot many things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is Not Love</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/what-is-not-love/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 10:12:30 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/what-is-not-love/</guid>
      <description>This youtube video(click the title, that is how bookmarks are arranged for all posts), is of Abraham Joshua Heshel Twerski, an Israeli-American Hasidic rabbi, a scion of the Chernobyl Hasidic dynasty, and a psychiatrist specializing in substance abuse.
External-love is what I&amp;rsquo;m going to give, not what I&amp;rsquo;m going to get. (This line is bit vague)
I good line that i need to keep in check is:
 &amp;ldquo;People make serious mistake in thinking, that you give to those who you love, and the answer is you love to those whom you give&amp;rdquo; His point is, if I give something to you, I have invested myself in you, since self-love is given everybody loves themselves, now that part of me has become in you, there is part of me in you that I love.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>People Do Not Care</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/people-do-not-care/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 12:22:20 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/people-do-not-care/</guid>
      <description>You get up every morning.
You show up.
You do the right things.
You work really really hard.
Don’t cheat, don’t steal, don’t beg, don’t lie.
  Here is the honest truth – People don’t care!
People don’t care if you are doing the right thing.
They only care if you are doing the right thing for them.
 tldr : If they care they care, if they don&amp;rsquo;t they don&amp;rsquo;t and that shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be once concern.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video: A glimpse into ancient indian astronomy</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/video-a-glimpse-into-ancient-indian-astronomy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2020 20:18:01 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/video-a-glimpse-into-ancient-indian-astronomy/</guid>
      <description>Astrology has always intrigued me, specifically indian style of astrology, have heard a lot about it. Lunar calendar and rituals and traditions around it always facinate me a lot. I have some longing for it.
Haven&amp;rsquo;t worked on it much, but this video again brings those question back to me.
Path for me is language first, will have to learn sanskrit first, then i would have lot of venues open to me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Federation Is Worst of All Worlds</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/federation-is-worst-of-all-worlds/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 04:13:47 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/federation-is-worst-of-all-worlds/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
