<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Quantum Physics on knowledge base</title><link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/tags/quantum-physics/</link><description>Recent content in Quantum Physics on knowledge base</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 04:22:28 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kbs.murarisumit.in/tags/quantum-physics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What Is Spacetime in Einstein Theory</title><link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/en/f7de1f85aff4e3440204f197756f8b68/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 04:22:28 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/en/f7de1f85aff4e3440204f197756f8b68/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="reftext">
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>the laws of physics and the speed of light must be the same for all uniformly moving observers, regardless of their state of relative motion.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>For this to be true, space and time can no longer be independent. Rather, they are &amp;ldquo;converted&amp;rdquo; into each other in such a way as to keep the speed of light constant for all observers.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>(This is why moving objects appear to shrink, as suspected by FitzGerald and Lorentz, and why moving observers may measure time differently, as speculated by Poincaré.) Space and time are relative (i.e., they depend on the motion of the observer who measures them) and light is more fundamental than either.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;div class="reftext-link">
&lt;a href="https://einstein.stanford.edu/SPACETIME/spacetime2.html" style="color: #828282;"> https://einstein.stanford.edu/SPACETIME/spacetime2.html&lt;/a>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>** Note: I don&amp;rsquo;t have intuition about spacetime in Einstein theory. **&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="what-is-spacetime-in-einstein-theory-">What is spacetime in Einstein theory ?&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>It&amp;rsquo;s like all objects in the universe sit in a smooth, four-dimensional fabric called space-time.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>This fabric is curved by the mass and energy of objects in it.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The curvature of space-time causes objects to move on curved paths. We see these paths as the force of gravity.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>This fabric is not just space and time, but a combination of both. It&amp;rsquo;s like a 4D fabric where 3D is space and 1D is time.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Now to me this fabric thing confuses me. This just doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel right to me.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>Reference:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://einstein.stanford.edu/SPACETIME/spacetime2.html">https://einstein.stanford.edu/SPACETIME/spacetime2.html&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.space.com/end-of-einstein-space-time">https://www.space.com/end-of-einstein-space-time&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>What Is Gravity</title><link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/en/cd0225c83fc890539178b33340888ea1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 04:20:30 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/en/cd0225c83fc890539178b33340888ea1/</guid><description>&lt;p>We have seen whenever we throw some object, after it loses the energy we gave it. It gets acceleration towards the earth as if earth is pulling it towards itself.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>This &lt;a href="https://kbs.murarisumit.in/en/c6e8cea33966964777e8ec8b34a71cef">acceleration&lt;/a> is 9.8 m/s^2 on earth, 1.6 m/s^2 on the moon, 3.7 m/s^2 on Mars etc.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>This acceleration is 0 m/s^2 in space.
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>So, if we throw some object in space, it will keep moving in the same direction. It will not come back to us.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="newtons-theory-of-gravity">Newton&amp;rsquo;s theory of gravity&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Newton had his theory why we feel this acceleration. He said that mass attracts mass.
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Hence earth attracts us. So, we feel a force that pulls us towards the earth. This force is called gravity.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="einsteins-theory-of-gravity">Einstein&amp;rsquo;s theory of gravity&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Einstein had his theory on how this force comes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>He said that mass bends the &lt;a href="https://kbs.murarisumit.in/en/f7de1f85aff4e3440204f197756f8b68/">space-time&lt;/a> around it. So, objects are pulled towards the mass. This bending of space-time is called gravity.
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>So here even the particle with no mass is pulled towards the mass. Because mass bends the space-time around it.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Whatever the theory of origin of this force, we found that earth &amp;amp; other planets pull objects towards themselves which causes acceleration. This acceleration is called gravity.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Mass vs matter ?</title><link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/en/4710840f1b6de62e27bbf0bf75af303e/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 23:46:01 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/en/4710840f1b6de62e27bbf0bf75af303e/</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="mass-vs-matter-">Mass vs matter ?&lt;/h4>
&lt;div class="reftext">
&lt;p>Mass is a measure of an object&amp;rsquo;s inertia and is quantified in terms of kilograms or grams, while matter refers to anything that occupies space and has mass.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Matter is all the “stuff” that exists in the universe. It has both mass and volume. Mass measures the amount of matter in a substance or an object. The basic SI unit for mass is the kilogram (kg).11&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Matter is anything that occupies space (having volume) and has mass is used to measure the amount of matter in a substance or an object.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Still this confused me, not able to intitutively, what is &amp;ldquo;mass&amp;rdquo; and what is &amp;ldquo;matter&amp;rdquo; ?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bit more detailed explanation:&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="q-what-is-matter-">Q: What is matter ?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>We are made of matter We are made of cells, tissues, and organs. These are all made of atoms and molecules. The rabbit is made of matter.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="q-what-is-mass-">Q: What is mass ?&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Mass is a property of a physical body.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>We take that every physical body has property called mass.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>^We assume it and take if fundamental property like charge on electron.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>It determines its acceleration in the presence of an applied force similar to ‘charge in electro-magnetic field’.&lt;br>
It is the same whether we are on Earth, the Moon, or in space.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="q-if-mass--weight-the-same-if-not-then-what-is-the-difference-">Q: If mass &amp;amp; weight the same, if not then what is the difference ?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>No, mass and weight are not the same. Mass we&amp;rsquo;ve read above, while weight is the force of gravity acting on an object.If weight &amp;amp; mass are different, then&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Why:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>We say we have a weight of 70 kg not mass of 70 kg.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Does weighting machine show mass or weight ?&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>To understand weight, we need to understand gravity.
&lt;details class="details"
style="border: 1px solid #ccc; border-radius: 5px; padding: 5px;"
>
&lt;summary>
What is gravity
&lt;/summary>
Read more about &lt;a href="https://kbs.murarisumit.in/en/cd0225c83fc890539178b33340888ea1/">What is gravity&lt;/a>
&lt;/details>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So weight is what we feel because of gravity. Because some acceleration is acting on us. How that acceleration comes is different &amp;amp; everyone has their own theory. &lt;a href="https://kbs.murarisumit.in/en/cd0225c83fc890539178b33340888ea1/">Read gravity&lt;/a> to know more about it.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Weight is measured &lt;code>kg * meter/second^2&lt;/code>. It is also called &amp;ldquo;Newton&amp;rdquo; in physics.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Newton is the force required to accelerate a 1kg mass at 1m/s for 1 second.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Read more about &lt;a href="https://kbs.murarisumit.in/en/c6e8cea33966964777e8ec8b34a71cef/">Understanding Physics Units in Basic Form&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="q-if-weight-in-newtonenc6e8cea33966964777e8ec8b34a71cef-then-why-weighting-machine-show-70kg-then-">Q: If weight in &lt;a href="https://kbs.murarisumit.in/en/c6e8cea33966964777e8ec8b34a71cef/">Newton&lt;/a>, then why weighting machine show 70kg then ?&amp;quot;&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>On earth our weighing machines are calibrated to show our weight in kg. But it is actually showing our mass in kg. This is because the standard gravitational acceleration on Earth is assumed, and weighing machines are calibrated to show &amp;ldquo;weight&amp;rdquo; in kilograms, which is a bit of a misnomer because kilograms technically measure mass, not weight&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If we took an earth calibration weighing machine to the moon, it would show our weight much less than 70 kg. But our mass would still be 70 kg. Because the weighing machine is calibrated to show weight on earth. If someone calibrated it to show weight on the moon, it would show 70 kg.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>