<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Skills on knowledge base</title><link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/tags/skills/</link><description>Recent content in Skills on knowledge base</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 23:41:17 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kbs.murarisumit.in/tags/skills/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Nithin Kamath of Zerodha Says True Financial Freedom Is About Acquiring Skills First Than Money</title><link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/60cdd644ced2abd406c37a892f8386e3/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 23:41:17 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/60cdd644ced2abd406c37a892f8386e3/</guid><description>&lt;p>This guy is simple to understand, no out of the world quotations. Can relate to him, seems like a neighbourhood elder brother(bhaiya) who you can talk to.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What he mentioned was, spend on skills. More like one message in a 3-idiot movie. Run after excellence, success will come to you. He isn&amp;rsquo;t sadhu and adds on to say to buy material assets like cars or houses. If a house gives peace of mind, improves quality of life, go buy a house. If cars make your life easy, use it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another important thing he mentioned is, we have to make money work for us to be financially independent and financial freedom is about being content. There are endless materialistic traps.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Just to few more bits to the post. &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kvBZjKXVyP8&amp;t=399s">There are three important assets&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Time&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Money&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Skills&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>We need to optimise on these three bits.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Learning to Write With Confidencce</title><link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/learning-to-write-with-confidence/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 20:42:29 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/learning-to-write-with-confidence/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="some-notes">Some notes&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="writing-is-thinking">Writing is Thinking&lt;/h3>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Self-doubt can be an ally. This is because it serves as an indicator of aspiration. It reflects love, love of something we dream of doing, and desire, desire to do it. If you find yourself asking yourself (and your friends), &amp;ldquo;Am I really a writer? Am I really an artist?&amp;rdquo; chances are you are.&amp;rdquo; - The War of Art&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Each time you write a page, you are a writer. Each time you practice the violin, you are a musician. Each time you start a workout, you are an athlete. Each time you encourage your employees, you are a leader.&amp;rdquo; - Atomic Habits&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;It’s through writing that we exercise our ability to think; they’re not mutually exclusive tasks.&amp;rdquo; - Grammarly&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h3 id="optimizing-for-one-variable">Optimizing for One Variable&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>This clearly isn’t always to my advantage, but it gives me something to orient around. If I tried to optimize completely across quality, speed, SEO-potential, among other variables, I would get paralyzed. So instead, I focus on one thing: quality.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="heading">&lt;/h3></description></item></channel></rss>