<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tils on Tils and bookmarks</title>
    <link>https://www.yinyangi.in/kbs/til/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tils on Tils and bookmarks</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 09:24:33 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.yinyangi.in/kbs/til/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>IPv4 Link Local</title>
      <link>https://www.yinyangi.in/kbs/til/ipv4-link-local/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 09:24:33 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.yinyangi.in/kbs/til/ipv4-link-local/</guid>
      <description>To participate in wide-area IP networking, a host needs to be configured with IP addresses for its interfaces, either manually by the user or automatically from a source on the network such as a Dynamic Host Configuration Protocol (DHCP) server. Unfortunately, such address configuration information may not always be available. It is therefore beneficial for a host to be able to depend on a useful subset of IP networking functions even when no address configuration is available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KISS</title>
      <link>https://www.yinyangi.in/kbs/til/kiss/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 19:18:04 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.yinyangi.in/kbs/til/kiss/</guid>
      <description>KISS is an acronym for &amp;ldquo;Keep it simple stupid&amp;rdquo; (notice no comma).
Stupid does not refer to the user. To quote Wikipedia:
 The principle is best exemplified by the story of Johnson handing a team of design engineers a handful of tools, with the challenge that the jet aircraft they were designing must be repairable by
an average mechanic in the field under combat conditions with only these tools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Change Orientation of an Image</title>
      <link>https://www.yinyangi.in/kbs/til/change-orientation-of-an-image/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 17:30:23 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.yinyangi.in/kbs/til/change-orientation-of-an-image/</guid>
      <description>A single-line CSS transform is all it takes to change the orientation of an image (or any DOM element, really).
For instance, if I have an image that is on its side, I can use the following rotate transform to orient it correctly.
1 2 3  img { transform: rotate(90deg); }   Testing you babay
1 2  import os os.path.join()    Go hello world
1 2 3 4 5 6 7  import ( &amp;#34;fmt&amp;#34; ) func main() { fmt.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>