<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>motivation on knowledge base</title>
    <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/tags/motivation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in motivation on knowledge base</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 23:33:57 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kbs.murarisumit.in/tags/motivation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Use Money to Buy Time</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/3f0f98b1a3c3258c2a2f705d58bb3595/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 23:33:57 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/3f0f98b1a3c3258c2a2f705d58bb3595/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you have enough to get basic life go by(for needs not for greed), extra money should be used to buy time. Initially you need t sell your time to make money, once there, basic needs taken care of start using money to buy time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tweet was inspired was&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take every opportunity you get to use money to buy time, and then proceed to “waste” that extra time in doing things that cannot be bought for money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are few things money can&amp;rsquo;t buy for me like health, family, friendship, trust etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply enjoy life to fullest to whatever be your defination. Money if very important part of life, but shouldn&amp;rsquo;t become life. Life is much more than that.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ankurwarikoo 41 Things at 41</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/1e0b24f24f6a5963366cc66d84ad098f/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2021 16:56:43 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/1e0b24f24f6a5963366cc66d84ad098f/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Read it somewhere, you can&amp;rsquo;t make mistakes. You&amp;rsquo;ve to learn from others&#39; mistakes/experiences. Read this post from &lt;a href=&#34;https://ankurwarikoo.com/contact/&#34;&gt;ankur warikoo&lt;/a&gt;, so thought of writing about it, to internalize it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Funny one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The only success for a company is when it raises money from customers. Congratulations when raising from money from founder is like, congratulating chef on buying vegetables&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Useful&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you share your failure openly, you instantly take away all the power    that the world had over you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s similar to 8 mile &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xh1ROLEDyP4&amp;amp;t=170s&#34;&gt;last rap battle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Managing your time is about managing your energy, managing your energy is about managing your attention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For me also, it is all about your focus and this is especially relevant in time where there are all fun and good youtube videos around to take your time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take criticism seriously but not personally&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This has been my journey, has been detached from surroundings but still not taking unwarranted criticism(which you don&amp;rsquo;t agree to) personally should be part of my journey. Understanding it&amp;rsquo;s their opinion and still choice is with me how I take it up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Also need to internalise response vs react. Always respond not react. You should not give anyone power over you, on how you response, that should only be yours and yours only.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;World doesn&amp;rsquo;t need one more template, world need one more rebel&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a good food for thought #food-for-thought&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Never complain&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remember this, have learnt it the hard way. Whatever it is, just don&amp;rsquo;t complain. It would never fix things, just aggravate them. Learn to handle them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The decision that will hurt you the most is not making one while waiting to take the right one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FOr waiting for the right time, has hurt more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Dark Knight Rises the Climb Scene</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/82f13670d5d8ce84febcb23889eea474/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 03:35:52 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/82f13670d5d8ce84febcb23889eea474/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One more youtube video, batman this time. This scene might have given goose bumps to Roger Federer too, you may fall but it&amp;rsquo;s what you choose afterwards that matters the most.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also the dialogue from rocky comes to my mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It ain&amp;rsquo;t about how hard you hit; It&amp;rsquo;s about how hard you can get hit and keep moving forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American nationalism had brought beautiful movies out there and something to learn from. Deserters/Refugees coming from every parts of world and joining together and making a &lt;strong&gt;great&lt;/strong&gt; nation. Nation making is huge task, India still isn&amp;rsquo;t a nation yet despite such commonality, history and culture, but American built nation from deserters, some refugees true but most deserters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Always in awe to see to see American might and what they have achieved. They really are a nation to look upto.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Novak Djokovic vs Roger Federer Wimbledon 2019 FullMatch</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/3eea4986a87740003aa7e5b40354ce03/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Aug 2021 04:57:43 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/3eea4986a87740003aa7e5b40354ce03/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One more djo&amp;rsquo;s match, but was looking at federer who showed his metal at 36 yrs of age.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jordan Peterson Successful Men Are Insane and Work All the Time</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/ce39966c39f2ea7d1a55946669a84685/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Aug 2021 01:51:32 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/ce39966c39f2ea7d1a55946669a84685/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;He said in one of his interviews that men wrote to him and told that he changed his life. I&amp;rsquo;m one of such characters. Here also a lot of thanks goes to people who made the internet happen, so I could watch his lessons/lectures or speeches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To achieve to be highly successful in corporate world i.e. reach at high position in social order one has to put insane amount of work, he mentioned 80 hours work week, translates to ~ 12 hours every day without breaks for years and with &lt;strong&gt;focus&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;determination&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;~hello~&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It isn&amp;rsquo;t like when kids go to work to the library to study for 6 hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;High social order always means different from different cultures. India had a weird culture once, people who left the material world and lived for pursuit of knowledge were treated on high pecking order, but that is for a very evolved state of culture. Mostly it would refer to high financial or political position.
Disclaimer: Today India is in a very sad state w.r.t its culture and the same system has become the biggest baggage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Will Mahatma Gandhi be treated in a higher social order than Bill Gates or Sir Albert Einstein ?
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One needs to make decision,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Either earn good enough money to enjoy life and then learn music, take care of body, tap-dancing, beautiful literature, learning physics, getting close to oneself/god&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be insane and work like crazy and get up in pecking order&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or third he didn&amp;rsquo;t mention having a middle ground, keep working your whole life because you enjoy it and reach in high pecking order. While taking care of your body, mind, being calm and happy all along in life. Is this route possible ?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLCE9046E85D3918D8&#34;&gt;Happiness Unlimited&lt;/a&gt; had a very huge impact on me, during my college years, but is this route possible? &lt;strong&gt;This would good exploration in my life&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    So goal of life is to explore this third route&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Novak Djokovic vs Rafael Nadal in the Longest Final in Grand Slam History</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/dba141a324349154865a7bdf421eee15/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Aug 2021 01:48:05 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/dba141a324349154865a7bdf421eee15/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If this can&amp;rsquo;t inspire anyone, not sure what could. These guys played for around ~ 6 hours, and that&amp;rsquo;s an incredible feat of achievement.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lin Dan vs Lee Chong Wei</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/lindan-vs-leechongwei/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 23:44:26 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/lindan-vs-leechongwei/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Seeing them together, playing with such skills is so beautiful. Love their game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great video compilation too.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>India&#39;s Maiden Indigenous Aircraft Carrier</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/india-maiden-indigenous-aircraft-carrier/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 22:48:36 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/india-maiden-indigenous-aircraft-carrier/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s is good to see fellow country man are working are making things are aircraft carrier, weighing 40000 tonnes in itself looks like huge engineering and manufacturing feat.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Profiles to Look Upto</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/profiles-to-look-upto/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 06:35:12 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/profiles-to-look-upto/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Time to time, few profiles come across to me, which I see and admire of, the amount of work they have done. The position they are in, the impact they are making. Seeing their profiles motivates me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These profile answer age old interview question for me: Where do you see youself in 3-5 years ?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His readme is beautiful, simple and succint. His github is clean. Motivated me also collect those badges(certifications), never a certification guy, but those badges are looking cool.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>

