<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>motivation on knowledge base</title>
    <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/tags/motivation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in motivation on knowledge base</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Aug 2021 01:51:32 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kbs.murarisumit.in/tags/motivation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Jordan Peterson Successful Men Are Insane and Work All the Time</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/ce39966c39f2ea7d1a55946669a84685/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Aug 2021 01:51:32 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/ce39966c39f2ea7d1a55946669a84685/</guid>
      <description>He said in one of his interviews that men wrote to him and told that he changed his life. I&amp;rsquo;m one of such characters. Here also a lot of thanks goes to people who made the internet happen, so I could watch his lessons/lectures or speeches.
To achieve to be highly successful in corporate world i.e. reach at high position in social order one has to put insane amount of work, he mentioned 80 hours work week, translates to ~ 12 hours every day without breaks for years and with focus and determination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Novak Djokovic vs Rafael Nadal in the Longest Final in Grand Slam History</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/dba141a324349154865a7bdf421eee15/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Aug 2021 01:48:05 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/dba141a324349154865a7bdf421eee15/</guid>
      <description>If this can&amp;rsquo;t inspire anyone, not sure what could. These guys played for around ~ 6 hours, and that&amp;rsquo;s an incredible feat of achievement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lin Dan vs Lee Chong Wei</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/lindan-vs-leechongwei/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 23:44:26 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/lindan-vs-leechongwei/</guid>
      <description>Seeing them together, playing with such skills is so beautiful. Love their game.
Great video compilation too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>India&#39;s Maiden Indigenous Aircraft Carrier</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/india-maiden-indigenous-aircraft-carrier/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 22:48:36 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/india-maiden-indigenous-aircraft-carrier/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s is good to see fellow country man are working are making things are aircraft carrier, weighing 40000 tonnes in itself looks like huge engineering and manufacturing feat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Profiles to Look Upto</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/profiles-to-look-upto/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 06:35:12 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/profiles-to-look-upto/</guid>
      <description>Time to time, few profiles come across to me, which I see and admire of, the amount of work they have done. The position they are in, the impact they are making. Seeing their profiles motivates me.
These profile answer age old interview question for me: Where do you see youself in 3-5 years ?
His readme is beautiful, simple and succint. His github is clean. Motivated me also collect those badges(certifications), never a certification guy, but those badges are looking cool.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
