<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>mentorship on knowledge base</title>
    <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/tags/mentorship/</link>
    <description>Recent content in mentorship on knowledge base</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 09:34:57 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kbs.murarisumit.in/tags/mentorship/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Leaving current org, risk and rewards</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/tils/leaving-exising-org-risk-rewards/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 09:34:57 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/tils/leaving-exising-org-risk-rewards/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Background:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There have been few things and also got new opportunities hence been planning to leave the existing org, meanwhile was having discussion my mentor(will ask him if I can put his name here) about my change and got really nice quote from him
While changing of jobs you need to think in terms of &lt;strong&gt;risk and reward&lt;/strong&gt;, and also one side quote &lt;code&gt;the devil you know is better than one you don&#39;t.&lt;/code&gt; (don&amp;rsquo;t&amp;rsquo; mean literal &lt;code&gt;devil&lt;/code&gt; here but hope you understand meaning behind quote)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;risk&#34;&gt;Risk:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you join a new org, you are leaving something you know about(devil you know), how it functions and how to get things done there . When you move to a new org, you don&amp;rsquo;t know how it works, it&amp;rsquo;s a new cognitive load. Hence the risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;reward&#34;&gt;Reward:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One reward that you see directly is compensation. It gets balanced with industry standards, not sure why it is so. Same person in the org is not compensated like a new employee coming in. It&amp;rsquo;s more like you don&amp;rsquo;t treat your current customer well and spend a lot of money on marketing to acquire new customers. There might be some reason probably a bit more google someday #todo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other important one is: sometimes if you&amp;rsquo;re really disgusted by the place you work in, a new workplace gives you a new fresh experience and meeting and working with new peers would be a great learning experience.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>

