<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>life-lessons on knowledge base</title>
    <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/tags/life-lessons/</link>
    <description>Recent content in life-lessons on knowledge base</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Aug 2021 01:51:32 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kbs.murarisumit.in/tags/life-lessons/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Jordan Peterson Successful Men Are Insane and Work All the Time</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/ce39966c39f2ea7d1a55946669a84685/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Aug 2021 01:51:32 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/ce39966c39f2ea7d1a55946669a84685/</guid>
      <description>He said in one of his interviews that men wrote to him and told that he changed his life. I&amp;rsquo;m one of such characters. Here also a lot of thanks goes to people who made the internet happen, so I could watch his lessons/lectures or speeches.
To achieve to be highly successful in corporate world i.e. reach at high position in social order one has to put insane amount of work, he mentioned 80 hours work week, translates to ~ 12 hours every day without breaks for years and with focus and determination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Novak Djokovic vs Rafael Nadal in the Longest Final in Grand Slam History</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/dba141a324349154865a7bdf421eee15/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Aug 2021 01:48:05 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/dba141a324349154865a7bdf421eee15/</guid>
      <description>If this can&amp;rsquo;t inspire anyone, not sure what could. These guys played for around ~ 6 hours, and that&amp;rsquo;s an incredible feat of achievement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leadership Lecture Sam Manekshaw</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/leadership-lecture-field-marshall-sam-mannekshaw/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 09:41:06 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/leadership-lecture-field-marshall-sam-mannekshaw/</guid>
      <description>He believes leaders are not born, you can make a leaders out of man with reasonable common-sense and decency and rest of portion he then mentions attributes of leadership.
Most of part is taken from summarized transcript by fellow youtuber at video with little changes from my side.
According to manekshaw sir qualities of leader   Professional competence : He provided example of Defence Minister who had no idea about howitzer, motor etc how can he lead the army officers !</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do Work With Joy</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/tils/do-work-with-joy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2020 17:43:03 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/tils/do-work-with-joy/</guid>
      <description>Don&amp;rsquo;t give up because it&amp;rsquo;s hard, if you love it: &amp;ldquo;do it&amp;rdquo;. It has to be done with joy, there is no point of adding more misery to our little world
Work should be done because you want to do it, you like it. It would bring best from you, else whole point of living life miserably doesn&amp;rsquo;t make sense. No point of doing work which you don&amp;rsquo;t like in life, that life is not a full life, and life should be lived fully, joyfully.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
