<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>life-lessons on knowledge base</title>
    <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/tags/life-lessons/</link>
    <description>Recent content in life-lessons on knowledge base</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 09:41:06 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kbs.murarisumit.in/tags/life-lessons/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Leadership Lecture Sam Manekshaw</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/leadership-lecture-field-marshall-sam-mannekshaw/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 09:41:06 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/leadership-lecture-field-marshall-sam-mannekshaw/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;He believes leaders are not born but made. You can make a leaders out of man with reasonable common-sense and decency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: Most of part is taken from summarized transcript by fellow youtuber at video with little changes from my side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to manekshaw sir qualities of leader&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Professional competence&lt;/strong&gt; : He provided example of Defence Minister.  That minister had no idea about howitzer, motor etc how can he lead the army officers !!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ability to take a decision and take a full responsibility for it.&lt;/strong&gt; : 👉🏻 Act of omission is much worse than act of commission of wrong. 👉🏻 why a person don’t take decision?? because he lacks confidence!! why? because he lacks professional knowledge.  👉🏻 If you must be a &lt;strong&gt;bloody fool&lt;/strong&gt; be must quickly - manekshawism
Absolute justice and impartiality: People may not like you but you would be respected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Courage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;👉🏻 moral courage: Ability to distinguish right from wrong. Then standby it, irrespective of what others think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;👉🏻 yes man, is a horrible man. He may rise very high, but will never become leader. He will be used by superior and disliked by colleagues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;👉🏻 He mentioned story, when he was summoned. This was during east Pakistan crisis, by Indira Gandhi and cabinet ministers. Cabinet ministers in meeting  expected him to be agree to intervene in april month. This not prudent and he boldly put forward his dissent about choice of time rather than being yes-man.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;👉🏻 physical courage: Everyone is scared, he tells he was scared too. To be a leader, one to have to physical courageous in face of adversity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He mentioned a story, where his subordinate threatened that he would kill him. That chap was big but he despite being scared, he made him santri for night. Also asked him to bring tea and hot water to him in morning. He had option to have more security around him, but he showed he has courage and also showing trust in his men. Funnily he goes on to say, don’t be fool-hardy like he was but we need to understand the idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Loyalty&lt;/strong&gt; : Its two way thing, one can rightfully demand it from subordinate if he is also loyal to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Management of men and sources: He mostly conveyed about role of emotional intelligence. Human have problems so being stern should be combined with human touch and sense of humour play a great role in it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Discipline and Character&lt;/strong&gt; No amount leadership would put things right, the two other important aspect(that we usually lack)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;👉🏻 Discipline&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discipline is code of conduct for decent living in society one with the other. This code of conduct has come from generation to generation, it’s come from holy books. It gets refined on as cultures change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Example: Non-punctuality is an act of ill-discipline. Very harmful for society and nation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;👉🏻 Character&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should be honest, truthful etc. The big picture is, knowing what you are. Do not let fans or hangers-on put you on pedestals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do watch the video, if you have time. You can learn lessons on how to communicates. Sweet little jokes he cracks, makes it far insightful than above mentioned transcript&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Treat Yourself</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/ccc19b24a5adb9a623a9f2c3383d750e/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 07:32:05 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/ccc19b24a5adb9a623a9f2c3383d750e/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Treat yourself as If you were someone that you are responsible for helping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read somewhere in internet and find it beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Money to Buy Time</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/3f0f98b1a3c3258c2a2f705d58bb3595/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 23:33:57 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/3f0f98b1a3c3258c2a2f705d58bb3595/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you have enough to get basic life go by(for needs not for greed), extra money should be used to buy time. Initially you need t sell your time to make money, once there, basic needs taken care of start using money to buy time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tweet was inspired was&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take every opportunity you get to use money to buy time, and then proceed to “waste” that extra time in doing things that cannot be bought for money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are few things money can&amp;rsquo;t buy for me like health, family, friendship, trust etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply enjoy life to fullest to whatever be your defination. Money if very important part of life, but shouldn&amp;rsquo;t become life. Life is much more than that.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Never Let the Future Disturb You</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/586a1c7bfad52e25a95e1d7d9654157a/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 11:41:47 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/586a1c7bfad52e25a95e1d7d9654157a/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t let your future disturb you. You will meet if you have to, with the same weapons of reason which today arm you against present&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If sometimes your future haunts you, for me personally someone close to me told a prophecy about me and it haunted me way longer than it should, hence was able to connect to it. IMO these things haunt the weak more than man of actions and yes reading does empower you against such weak thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This quote from  bhagavad geeta helps me keep on the right track, and yes evening prayers do help me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;कर्मण्येवाधिकारस्ते मा फलेषु कदाचन |
मा कर्मफलहेतुर्भूर्मा ते सङ्गोऽस्त्वकर्मणि || 47 ||&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You have a right to perform your prescribed duties&lt;/strong&gt;, but you are not entitled to the fruits of your actions. Never consider yourself to be the cause of the results of your activities, nor be attached to inaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the future haunts you, remember, that is not in your control. No worry/stress can solve it. Only things that can help you are your actions and what you choose to do. Remember the only thing that is in your control are your actions coupled with weapons/fruit of reason/बुद्धि no more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No worry can solve issues other than your actions which are in your control.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jordan Peterson Successful Men Are Insane and Work All the Time</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/ce39966c39f2ea7d1a55946669a84685/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Aug 2021 01:51:32 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/ce39966c39f2ea7d1a55946669a84685/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;He said in one of his interviews that men wrote to him and told that he changed his life. I&amp;rsquo;m one of such characters. Here also a lot of thanks goes to people who made the internet happen, so I could watch his lessons/lectures or speeches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To achieve to be highly successful in corporate world i.e. reach at high position in social order one has to put insane amount of work, he mentioned 80 hours work week, translates to ~ 12 hours every day without breaks for years and with &lt;strong&gt;focus&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;determination&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;~hello~&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It isn&amp;rsquo;t like when kids go to work to the library to study for 6 hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;High social order always means different from different cultures. India had a weird culture once, people who left the material world and lived for pursuit of knowledge were treated on high pecking order, but that is for a very evolved state of culture. Mostly it would refer to high financial or political position.
Disclaimer: Today India is in a very sad state w.r.t its culture and the same system has become the biggest baggage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Will Mahatma Gandhi be treated in a higher social order than Bill Gates or Sir Albert Einstein ?
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One needs to make decision,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Either earn good enough money to enjoy life and then learn music, take care of body, tap-dancing, beautiful literature, learning physics, getting close to oneself/god&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be insane and work like crazy and get up in pecking order&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or third he didn&amp;rsquo;t mention having a middle ground, keep working your whole life because you enjoy it and reach in high pecking order. While taking care of your body, mind, being calm and happy all along in life. Is this route possible ?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLCE9046E85D3918D8&#34;&gt;Happiness Unlimited&lt;/a&gt; had a very huge impact on me, during my college years, but is this route possible? &lt;strong&gt;This would good exploration in my life&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    So goal of life is to explore this third route&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Novak Djokovic vs Rafael Nadal in the Longest Final in Grand Slam History</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/dba141a324349154865a7bdf421eee15/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Aug 2021 01:48:05 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/dba141a324349154865a7bdf421eee15/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If this can&amp;rsquo;t inspire anyone, not sure what could. These guys played for around ~ 6 hours, and that&amp;rsquo;s an incredible feat of achievement.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do Work With Joy</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/tils/do-work-with-joy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2020 17:43:03 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/tils/do-work-with-joy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t give up because it&amp;rsquo;s hard, if you love it: &amp;ldquo;do it&amp;rdquo;. It has to be done with joy, there is no point of adding more misery to our little world&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Work should be done because you want to do it, you like it. It would bring best from you, else whole point of living life miserably doesn&amp;rsquo;t make sense.
No point of doing work which you don&amp;rsquo;t like in life, that life is not a full life, and life should be lived fully, joyfully.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sure there will be problems while doing work you like to do, those problems are worth solving and putting head into. It might be because what you want other people also want, which takes away the thing you want and like. There you need to show your determination, survival skills but use them for the job you like to do.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>

