<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2022 on knowledge base</title>
    <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/year/2022/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2022 on knowledge base</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 10:01:50 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kbs.murarisumit.in/year/2022/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Decision Making Tricks</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/71cf6d3f5df8908b988630bd57c2541e/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 10:01:50 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/71cf6d3f5df8908b988630bd57c2541e/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Came to this blog from @navelism bot, which shared this &amp;ldquo;If you can&amp;rsquo;t decide, the answer is no.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So big takeaways which made to space repitition were&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;naval-ravikant-if-you-cant-decide-the-answer-is-no&#34;&gt;Naval Ravikant: If You Can&amp;rsquo;t Decide, The Answer Is No.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you cannot decide, the answer is no. And the reason is, modern society is full of options. There are tons and tons of options. We live on a planet of seven billion people, and we are connected to everybody on the internet. There are hundreds of thousands of careers available to you. There are so many choices. You’re biologically not built to realize how many choices there are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s very, very important we only say yes when we are pretty certain. You’re never going to be absolutely certain, but you’re going to be very certain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;nassim-nicholas-taleb-you-only-need-one-reason-to-do-something&#34;&gt;Nassim Nicholas Taleb: You Only Need One Reason To Do Something.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have more than one reason to do something… just don’t do it. It does not mean that one reason is better than two, just that by invoking more than one reason you are trying to convince yourself to do something. Obvious decisions (robust to error) require no more than a single reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was common theme Warren Buffet and Charlie Munger views on picking stocks. &lt;strong&gt;We only need one reason to reject, and choice should be obivious.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stock Market Investing Strategy</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/aa68a2a28a8178304a35c8339a99d5f2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 07:12:32 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/aa68a2a28a8178304a35c8339a99d5f2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the stock market, the most important organ is the stomach. It&amp;rsquo;s not the brain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;understand-what-you-own&#34;&gt;Understand what you own.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No use of checking everyday or getting stock calls. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t work. Understand what you invest in. You need to check quarterly reports, see if finances are in place. So when it falls, you can gauge if it&amp;rsquo;s  moment of panic or buying opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;understand-market&#34;&gt;Understand market.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understand the bear market is going to come, correction is always there. &lt;strong&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s inevitable&lt;/strong&gt;. He tells at time of video during 93 years of market, there was 10% falling(correction) 50 times. There was 25% falling(Bear market) of market almost ~6 years. &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_stock_market_crashes_and_bear_markets&#34;&gt;List_of_stock_market_crashes_and_bear_markets&lt;/a&gt;
If you understand what you own, then you will have stomach for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;when-to-sell-the-stock&#34;&gt;When to sell the stock&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you understand what you own, it becomes easier. If you still see room for growth continue, even if 5x, 10x stock has grown.  When you don&amp;rsquo;t see the growth, because you know it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;criteria-for-investing&#34;&gt;Criteria for investing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Choose less-debt companies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t invest with 1- 2 years in horizon. Have outlook of 10, 20 or 30 years.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;side-information&#34;&gt;Side information&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You don&amp;rsquo;t need many multi-bagger, only few for making lot of money.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t fall for how bad it can go. It can go fruther low and to the point of crash.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t keep stocks like family, treat them like utility.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stock goes up, I must right. Stock goes down, it must be wrong. &lt;strong&gt;This is wrong mindset&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>

