<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2021 on knowledge base</title>
    <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/year/2021/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2021 on knowledge base</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 12:50:34 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kbs.murarisumit.in/year/2021/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Awesome K8s Security</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/awesome-k8s-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 12:50:34 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/awesome-k8s-security/</guid>
      <description>A curated list for Kubernetes (K8s) Security resources such as articles, books, tools, talks and videos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sharingbuttons</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/sharingbuttons.io/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 11:50:41 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/sharingbuttons.io/</guid>
      <description>Not sure how reached here, wasn&amp;rsquo;t actively looking for it but glad found it. Not a fan of bulky tracking websites, so this social little privacy-centric media buttons for reader and myself make ton of sense to me.
Not a fan of twitter, but using twitter to reach out to people get feedback, improve ourselves, make myself better and this note is to remind myself why enabled this feature of social sharing in this site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo Good Archive Page</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/hugo-good-archive-page/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 09:39:45 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/hugo-good-archive-page/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s good archive page style, save time and easy navigation for website. Intent is to make archive page like this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayes Rule and Medical Tests</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/bayes-rule-medical-tests/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 08:54:42 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/bayes-rule-medical-tests/</guid>
      <description>All medical tests do is update their probability of having disease, and not tell if we have disease or not.
There are three things
 Prevalence : How common is that disease around here? What chance of having it without tests? Sensitivity : If even disease is present, how good is the test at detecting it. Specificity : If a test is taken, there can be other issues that result. Clots in the pancreas can be because of a lot many things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trust Your Instincts Instead of Hearsay</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/tils/trust-your-instincts-instead-of-hearsay/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 02:33:04 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/tils/trust-your-instincts-instead-of-hearsay/</guid>
      <description>More my understanding of the world grows by reading various prophecies people have made before, makes me realize that there is no point in taking hearsay seriously, be it from news channels, be it anywhere else. No one knows the future, it&amp;rsquo;s so obvious, still people are into prediction/criticism business and it&amp;rsquo;s working well too.
 In 1909 Washington Post wrote &amp;ldquo;There will never be such a thing as commercial aerial freighters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>India&#39;s Maiden Indigenous Aircraft Carrier</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/india-maiden-indigenous-aircraft-carrier/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 22:48:36 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/india-maiden-indigenous-aircraft-carrier/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s is good to see fellow country man are working are making things are aircraft carrier, weighing 40000 tonnes in itself looks like huge engineering and manufacturing feat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homelabs Setup</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/homelabs-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 22:24:23 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/homelabs-setup/</guid>
      <description>For sometime having ideas of using homelabs, found this guide useful but have other important priorities right now. Hence parking it here for future referece.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bigger Impact of Distraction More Than Just Time Lost</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/bigger-impact-for-distraction-more-than-just-time-lost/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 09:48:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/bigger-impact-for-distraction-more-than-just-time-lost/</guid>
      <description>Somehow reached to this tacky/clickbaity title &amp;ldquo;How the smartphone is destroying you from inside&amp;rdquo; https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4HjC245ugW8. Probably from the past few days, putting my head to these distractions. They seem to me like modern day alcoholic drinks. You enjoy it and forget your problems, similar promises made by alcoholic drinks.
So the point video makes is, the time we invest in these addictive systems(there whole KPI is to make stay people on their website) is anyways gone, but there are more far reaching impact because of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finally Some Sense in Laptops</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/finally-some-sense-in-laptops/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 09:44:42 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/finally-some-sense-in-laptops/</guid>
      <description>It was good to see nice laptops coming in now. Which have this repairability in mind. This laptop specially looks with it&amp;rsquo;s modularity. As iFixit says, this is slippery slope, we have seen many such initiatives come and go. So hoping this works time and changes consumer electronics industry for good.
Kudos to https://frame.work/ team.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
