<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>quotes on knowledge base</title>
    <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/category/quotes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in quotes on knowledge base</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 07:32:05 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kbs.murarisumit.in/category/quotes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Treat Yourself</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/ccc19b24a5adb9a623a9f2c3383d750e/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 07:32:05 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/ccc19b24a5adb9a623a9f2c3383d750e/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Treat yourself as If you were someone that you are responsible for helping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read somewhere in internet and find it beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s Not What I Am Underneath it&#39;s What I Do Defines Me</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/9aed16443012e51a38b0c189b58f95ab/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 04:55:31 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/9aed16443012e51a38b0c189b58f95ab/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Have come to the conclusion that everyone sees a different movie in their head, even if they watch the same movie. It&amp;rsquo;s all in your state of your mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Used to think that what&amp;rsquo;s in head/thoughts matters but as grown up come to conclusion that &lt;strong&gt;no actions matters&lt;/strong&gt;, what you do defines you &lt;strong&gt;not just what you think&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Related quote: &lt;a href=&#34;https://kbs.murarisumit.in/586a1c7bfad52e25a95e1d7d9654157a/&#34;&gt;Never let the future disturb you&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Every Lie We Tell Incurs a Debt to the Truth. Sooner or Later That Debt Is Paid</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/quotes/every-lie-we-tell-incurs-a-debt-to-the-truth-sooner-or-later-that-debt-is-paid/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 00:31:04 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/quotes/every-lie-we-tell-incurs-a-debt-to-the-truth-sooner-or-later-that-debt-is-paid/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Update note on previous quote, there has been time when I have lied to close once and was in illusion that doing it for greater good. Learnt it the hard way that every lie we say incurs debt to truth, and eventually it is paid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Better it&amp;rsquo;s paid early, or you keep-on paying EMI in terms of stress and which in turn cause high blood pressure.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Never Let the Future Disturb You</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/586a1c7bfad52e25a95e1d7d9654157a/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 11:41:47 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/586a1c7bfad52e25a95e1d7d9654157a/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t let your future disturb you. You will meet if you have to, with the same weapons of reason which today arm you against present&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If sometimes your future haunts you, for me personally someone close to me told a prophecy about me and it haunted me way longer than it should, hence was able to connect to it. IMO these things haunt the weak more than man of actions and yes reading does empower you against such weak thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This quote from  bhagavad geeta helps me keep on the right track, and yes evening prayers do help me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;कर्मण्येवाधिकारस्ते मा फलेषु कदाचन |
मा कर्मफलहेतुर्भूर्मा ते सङ्गोऽस्त्वकर्मणि || 47 ||&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You have a right to perform your prescribed duties&lt;/strong&gt;, but you are not entitled to the fruits of your actions. Never consider yourself to be the cause of the results of your activities, nor be attached to inaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the future haunts you, remember, that is not in your control. No worry/stress can solve it. Only things that can help you are your actions and what you choose to do. Remember the only thing that is in your control are your actions coupled with weapons/fruit of reason/बुद्धि no more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No worry can solve issues other than your actions which are in your control.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Never Hate Bad Time</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/quotes/never-hate-bad-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 09:35:32 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/quotes/never-hate-bad-time/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Never hate bad time. It reveals your true friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ref: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/pranavmahajan/status/1420387769252126728&#34;&gt;https://twitter.com/pranavmahajan/status/1420387769252126728&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also one thing is learnt long back, and probably has become my nature. You can only have few friends with time you have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have more than three friends, probably you don&amp;rsquo;t have any.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is what my understanding as how now. Let see how it changes along with time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now while frequently update this site, thought came to my mind. How often would I come and read this and reason for putting thsese in public.  Probably if can keep this site running for 5, 10 or 20 years, would love to see how time has changed and how thought process has changed(including learning to use spellcheck in future ;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>

