<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lessons on knowledge base</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/lessons/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Lessons on knowledge base</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 13:31:22 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/lessons/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Handle Difficult Conversations</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/902781fdc500bf70b3f42eb1c2d67ae6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 13:31:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/902781fdc500bf70b3f42eb1c2d67ae6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I.AM.CALM model for handling difficult convesation, learnt it in grab, and found it helpful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do you handle difficult conversations with empathy and kindness? :thinking_face: Try the I.AM.CALM model below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I = Intent should be positive&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Phrase your intentions by sharing &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; AND &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A = Assumptions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identify your bias and ask questions to know the full story&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;M = Make it safe&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Encourage a safe environment by apologizing for your mistakes (if any) and establishing a mutual purpose.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;C = Clarify the facts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Separate fact from fiction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A = Ask for other&amp;rsquo;s viewpoint&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask open ended questions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;L = Listening&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paraphrase what you think the other person meant&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;M = Manage Resolution &amp;amp; Action&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explore win-win solutions and agree on next steps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ankurwarikoo 41 Things at 41</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/1e0b24f24f6a5963366cc66d84ad098f/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2021 16:56:43 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/1e0b24f24f6a5963366cc66d84ad098f/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Read it somewhere, you can&amp;rsquo;t make mistakes. You&amp;rsquo;ve to learn from others&amp;rsquo; mistakes/experiences. Read this post from &lt;a href=&#34;https://ankurwarikoo.com/contact/&#34;&gt;ankur warikoo&lt;/a&gt;, so thought of writing about it, to internalize it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Funny one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The only success for a company is when it raises money from customers. Congratulations when raising from money from founder is like, congratulating chef on buying vegetables&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Useful&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you share your failure openly, you instantly take away all the power    that the world had over you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s similar to 8 mile &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xh1ROLEDyP4&amp;t=170s&#34;&gt;last rap battle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Managing your time is about managing your energy, managing your energy is about managing your attention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For me also, it is all about your focus and this is especially relevant in time where there are all fun and good youtube videos around to take your time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take criticism seriously but not personally&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This has been my journey, has been detached from surroundings but still not taking unwarranted criticism(which you don&amp;rsquo;t agree to) personally should be part of my journey. Understanding it&amp;rsquo;s their opinion and still choice is with me how I take it up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Also need to internalise response vs react. Always respond not react. You should not give anyone power over you, on how you response, that should only be yours and yours only.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;World doesn&amp;rsquo;t need one more template, world need one more rebel&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a good food for thought #food-for-thought&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Never complain&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remember this, have learnt it the hard way. Whatever it is, just don&amp;rsquo;t complain. It would never fix things, just aggravate them. Learn to handle them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The decision that will hurt you the most is not making one while waiting to take the right one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FOr waiting for the right time, has hurt more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Wake Up Early</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/f2bc54ae2871f124a8777721f4ab3446/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 10:59:21 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/f2bc54ae2871f124a8777721f4ab3446/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;His blog post, keeping here for my reference:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;lntable&#34;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt; 1
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt; 2
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt; 3
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt; 4
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt; 5
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt; 6
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt; 7
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt; 8
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt; 9
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;10
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;11
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;12
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;13
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;14
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;15
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;16
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;17
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;18
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;19
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;20
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;21
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;22
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;One of the most frequently asked questions to me is: “How do you manage to wake up early?”
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;Logic says several answers to it:
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;    Keep your workout gear next to your bed
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;    Alarm clock in another room
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;    Burpees on waking up, etc.
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;All of these work, until they don’t.
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;The true question to address is “How to sleep on time?”
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;If you’re sleeping at 11 and want to wake up at 4, the motivation will certainly stop on Day 4.
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;What if we get a night-time schedule, that makes it impossible to sleep late? Something like:
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;    Having dinner 2-3 hours prior to planned bed time
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;    Spending time doing activities that relax you
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;    Planning for the next day
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;It turns out, if we turn to twist the outputs without changing the inputs, the motivation won’t lasts.
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;The more we strive to get the inputs right, the more the outputs automatically take care of themselves.
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Can attest to it, this has been the only thing working for me. If I sleep late, then its better to assume that mornings are gone now, nothing can be done, take it as holiday tomorrow. This also cements the idea in me that &lt;code&gt;my today defines my tomorrow&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mornings are the most beautiful and productive part of the day, and following is my routine, it might help you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday night&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have dinner by 6:30-7:00 and if it&amp;rsquo;s late go for a fruit diet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read books, listen to music, enjoy time with family, and basically spend time doing activities that relax you (as ankur mentioned).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Having milk before sleeping with turmeric is good. Somehow flavour is good to me, also a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dosha&#34;&gt;khapa guy&lt;/a&gt;, so that works for me, might now work for you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plan things for tomorrow.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mornings&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wake up by 3:30/4/4:30, pick tasks you&amp;rsquo;ve planned and chop them off. You get beautiful those feel-good feelings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go and see the sun rise, for me it&amp;rsquo;s beautiful and other &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thesaurus.com/browse/beautiful&#34;&gt;adjectives&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exercise after saying &lt;strong&gt;hi&lt;/strong&gt; to the sun.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cook food and be happy as you are so lucky to have that.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Before eating, take a bath and freshen up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eat food and now the day starts for me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plan is to add morning prayers into this, but don&amp;rsquo;t have a pooja room in the house(have to do something for it.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afternoon&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This time is sold to someone else for money(sad but that&amp;rsquo;s case for now[27-Aug-2021])&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I sleep late,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No fun mornings, admitting I have missed all of that for today.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No alarm, but body sleep is important to me, no alarm to disturb it. Have done my deeds. It&amp;rsquo;s fine, let this morning go. Nothing can be done about it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you can try to do something meaningful during the day, do that and remember most importantly sleep on time to enjoy your next morning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perception Is Reality</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/b4623554b68ff4565baac8390eee35e5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 06:04:14 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/b4623554b68ff4565baac8390eee35e5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Was writing a few posts on being a man of actions, not being scared of the future and remembering only action matters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;%7B%7B/586a1c7bfad52e25a95e1d7d9654157a/&#34;&gt;Not scared of future&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/9aed16443012e51a38b0c189b58f95ab&#34;&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s Not What I Am Underneath it&amp;rsquo;s What I Do Defines Me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Excerpts from notion kbs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Confidence is the key, if you believe in you the world will believe in you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perception is reality, how people perceive you is how they behave around you and that is real, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter if their perception is an accurate depiction of you or not because it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter. People do action, real world action based on it. Hence the &lt;strong&gt;Perception is reality or Perception becomes the reality.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I learnt it the hard way, when people perceive you in a certain way and action, real actions are taken because of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What people perceive of you are from your actions, at least this is the case with me. Your thoughts are not visible out there, only your actions. You can speak of your intention, and some people may buy it but not for long. Actions are more powerful than words.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leaving current org, risk and rewards</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/tils/leaving-exising-org-risk-rewards/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 09:34:57 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/tils/leaving-exising-org-risk-rewards/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Background:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There have been few things and also got new opportunities hence been planning to leave the existing org, meanwhile was having discussion my mentor(will ask him if I can put his name here) about my change and got really nice quote from him
While changing of jobs you need to think in terms of &lt;strong&gt;risk and reward&lt;/strong&gt;, and also one side quote &lt;code&gt;the devil you know is better than one you don&#39;t.&lt;/code&gt; (don&amp;rsquo;t&amp;rsquo; mean literal &lt;code&gt;devil&lt;/code&gt; here but hope you understand meaning behind quote)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;risk&#34;&gt;Risk:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you join a new org, you are leaving something you know about(devil you know), how it functions and how to get things done there . When you move to a new org, you don&amp;rsquo;t know how it works, it&amp;rsquo;s a new cognitive load. Hence the risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;reward&#34;&gt;Reward:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One reward that you see directly is compensation. It gets balanced with industry standards, not sure why it is so. Same person in the org is not compensated like a new employee coming in. It&amp;rsquo;s more like you don&amp;rsquo;t treat your current customer well and spend a lot of money on marketing to acquire new customers. There might be some reason probably a bit more google someday #todo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other important one is: sometimes if you&amp;rsquo;re really disgusted by the place you work in, a new workplace gives you a new fresh experience and meeting and working with new peers would be a great learning experience.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>People Do Not Care</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/bookmarks/people-do-not-care/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 12:22:20 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/bookmarks/people-do-not-care/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You get up every morning.&lt;br&gt;
You show up.&lt;br&gt;
You do the right things.&lt;br&gt;
You work really really hard.&lt;br&gt;
Don’t cheat, don’t steal, don’t beg, don’t lie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the honest truth – People don’t care!&lt;br&gt;
People don’t care if you are doing the right thing.&lt;br&gt;
They only care if you are doing the right thing for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;tldr : If they care they care, if they don&amp;rsquo;t they don&amp;rsquo;t and that shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be once concern.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Truely, it makes sense people would only care if you do right thing for them&lt;/strong&gt;, but that shouldn&amp;rsquo;t concern us. It is not in our control, so why worry in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reason for doing sometime should be because &lt;strong&gt;you care&lt;/strong&gt; not because someone else does. Personally learnt it hard way that people pleasing or doing because someone else wants/cares is stupid idea. For me personally, it was because I had low self-respect for myself.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Stopping Vim Now</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/decisions/why-stopping-vim-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 15:15:50 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/decisions/why-stopping-vim-now/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While learning more about tools for the trade, vim was the tool that was thrown at me a lot. This tool took a long time, because I went the wrong route and was trying to use it as IDE not how it was intended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The way I started was at first, moved to config and plugin, instead of getting comfortable with vim-help, docs or core-vim without any setting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I learnt a few things here like vim-fugitive, it&amp;rsquo;s a great plugin, and alone it makes vim a treat to use. It makes my git usage very easy, staging and selecting hunks became easy for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It works well for go and python and go still once in a while, but I still have to struggle with vim to get it work for me. I tend to spend time in my vim rather than working on problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It became more evident to me when I was watching a youtube video on binary exploitation series &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3NTXFUxcKPc&amp;list=PLhixgUqwRTjxglIswKp9mpkfPNfHkzyeN&amp;index=7&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3NTXFUxcKPc&amp;list=PLhixgUqwRTjxglIswKp9mpkfPNfHkzyeN&amp;index=7&lt;/a&gt;, and came across this tool &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/radare/radare2&#34;&gt;https://github.com/radare/radare2&lt;/a&gt;. It seemed similar to vim, and I thought for beginners the tools should be secondary but playing with art is more important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found similarities with learning badminton and drawing, focus on badminton as skill was more important. Focussed more on playing badminton, picked up any badminton racket and knew badminton racket wasn&amp;rsquo;t the bottleneck, my skills were. This was very evident to me, and was completely aware of that fact. People around me were buying head-heavy rackets, branded expensive rackets, for me 5min google and found a simple racket and just worked with that, nothing more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Same went with the drawing course that I took on udemy, I just picked a simple pencil, rubber and eraser and started working on skill, instead of focusing on the tool. Instead of blue pencil and different type of pencils.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But for a job, focussing on vim, is much trouble, it does things in an odd way, you need to learn it. It&amp;rsquo;s probably good for masters but for people like where bottleneck isn&amp;rsquo;t IDE but my skills focus should be on enhancing skills rather than tools for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tools do matter to me, tmux is one fantastic tool which I&amp;rsquo;ve picked up and I love to core. It&amp;rsquo;s a beautiful tool to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I will focus more on skills, like it worked for badminton and drawing will focus on creating products and instead of fighting with the system to get things done.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning to Write With Confidencce</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/bookmarks/learning-to-write-with-confidence/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 20:42:29 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/bookmarks/learning-to-write-with-confidence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;some-notes&#34;&gt;Some notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;writing-is-thinking&#34;&gt;Writing is Thinking&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Self-doubt can be an ally. This is because it serves as an indicator of aspiration. It reflects love, love of something we dream of doing, and desire, desire to do it. If you find yourself asking yourself (and your friends), &amp;ldquo;Am I really a writer? Am I really an artist?&amp;rdquo; chances are you are.&amp;rdquo; - The War of Art&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Each time you write a page, you are a writer. Each time you practice the violin, you are a musician. Each time you start a workout, you are an athlete. Each time you encourage your employees, you are a leader.&amp;rdquo; - Atomic Habits&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It’s through writing that we exercise our ability to think; they’re not mutually exclusive tasks.&amp;rdquo; - Grammarly&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;optimizing-for-one-variable&#34;&gt;Optimizing for One Variable&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This clearly isn’t always to my advantage, but it gives me something to orient around. If I tried to optimize completely across quality, speed, SEO-potential, among other variables, I would get paralyzed. So instead, I focus on one thing: quality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sell Yourself, Sell Your Work</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/bookmarks/sell-yourself-sell-your-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 08:39:21 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/bookmarks/sell-yourself-sell-your-work/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;few-notes&#34;&gt;Few notes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doing technically brilliant work may be enough for your personal gratification, but you should never think it&amp;rsquo;s enough. If you lock yourself in a room and do the most marvellous work but don&amp;rsquo;t tell anyone, then no one will know, no one will benefit, and the work will be lost. You may as well not have bothered. For the world to benefit from your work, and therefore for you to benefit fully from your work, you have to make it known.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;commentry&#34;&gt;Commentry&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Peter Thiel has an interesting take on sales in his book Zero to One. He makes the case that good selling and good teaching are pretty much the same thing. The best teachers know how to sell the topic they teach&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;personal-opinion&#34;&gt;Personal opinion&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The way i take it is, here it&amp;rsquo;s more about communicating well and and informing people about work you do, which is important imo too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something like Dropbox YC post: &lt;a href=&#34;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=8863&#34;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=8863&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Linus post on usenet for his little kernel that he created.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m doing a (free) operating system (just a hobby, won&amp;rsquo;t be big and professional like gnu) for 386(486) AT clones. This has been brewing since April, and is starting to get ready. I&amp;rsquo;d like any feedback on things people like/dislike in minix, as my OS resembles it somewhat (same physical layout of the file-system (due to practical reasons) among other things). I&amp;rsquo;ve currently ported bash(1.08) and gcc(1.40), and things seem to work. This implies that I&amp;rsquo;ll get something practical within a few months [&amp;hellip;] Yes - it&amp;rsquo;s free of any minix code, and it has a multi-threaded fs. It is NOT portable (uses 386 task switching etc), and it probably never will support anything other than AT-harddisks, as that&amp;rsquo;s all I have :-(.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For good work, one should communicate and inform it with people around him.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>

