<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>lessons on knowledge base</title>
    <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/tags/lessons/</link>
    <description>Recent content in lessons on knowledge base</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2021 16:56:43 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kbs.murarisumit.in/tags/lessons/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ankurwarikoo 41 Things at 41</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/1e0b24f24f6a5963366cc66d84ad098f/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2021 16:56:43 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/1e0b24f24f6a5963366cc66d84ad098f/</guid>
      <description>He turned 41 last week. Here are 41 reflections about his life, which he remain immensely grateful for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Wake Up Early</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/f2bc54ae2871f124a8777721f4ab3446/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 10:59:21 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/f2bc54ae2871f124a8777721f4ab3446/</guid>
      <description>Most beautiful part of day for me</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perception Is Reality</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/b4623554b68ff4565baac8390eee35e5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 06:04:14 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/b4623554b68ff4565baac8390eee35e5/</guid>
      <description>Was writing a few posts on being a man of actions, not being scared of the future and remembering only action matters.
 Not scared of future It&amp;rsquo;s Not What I Am Underneath it&amp;rsquo;s What I Do Defines Me  Excerpts from notion kbs
 Confidence is the key, if you believe in you the world will believe in you.
  Perception is reality, how people perceive you is how they behave around you and that is real, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter if their perception is an accurate depiction of you or not because it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leaving current org, risk and rewards</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/tils/leaving-exising-org-risk-rewards/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 09:34:57 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/tils/leaving-exising-org-risk-rewards/</guid>
      <description>Background:
There have been few things and also got new opportunities hence been planning to leave the existing org, meanwhile was having discussion my mentor(will ask him if I can put his name here) about my change and got really nice quote from him While changing of jobs you need to think in terms of risk and reward, and also one side quote the devil you know is better than one you don&#39;t.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>People Do Not Care</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/people-do-not-care/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 12:22:20 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/people-do-not-care/</guid>
      <description>You get up every morning.
You show up.
You do the right things.
You work really really hard.
Don’t cheat, don’t steal, don’t beg, don’t lie.
  Here is the honest truth – People don’t care!
People don’t care if you are doing the right thing.
They only care if you are doing the right thing for them.
 tldr : If they care they care, if they don&amp;rsquo;t they don&amp;rsquo;t and that shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be once concern.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Stopping Vim Now</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/decisions/why-stopping-vim-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 15:15:50 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/decisions/why-stopping-vim-now/</guid>
      <description>While learning more about tools for the trade, vim was the tool that was thrown at me a lot. This tool took a long time, because I went the wrong route and was trying to use it as IDE not how it was intended.
The way I started was at first, moved to config and plugin, instead of getting comfortable with vim-help, docs or core-vim without any setting.
I learnt a few things here like vim-fugitive, it&amp;rsquo;s a great plugin, and alone it makes vim a treat to use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning to Write With Confidencce</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/learning-to-write-with-confidence/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 20:42:29 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/learning-to-write-with-confidence/</guid>
      <description>Some notes Writing is Thinking  &amp;ldquo;Self-doubt can be an ally. This is because it serves as an indicator of aspiration. It reflects love, love of something we dream of doing, and desire, desire to do it. If you find yourself asking yourself (and your friends), &amp;ldquo;Am I really a writer? Am I really an artist?&amp;rdquo; chances are you are.&amp;rdquo; - The War of Art
  &amp;ldquo;Each time you write a page, you are a writer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sell Yourself, Sell Your Work</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/sell-yourself-sell-your-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 08:39:21 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/sell-yourself-sell-your-work/</guid>
      <description>Few notes Doing technically brilliant work may be enough for your personal gratification, but you should never think it&amp;rsquo;s enough. If you lock yourself in a room and do the most marvellous work but don&amp;rsquo;t tell anyone, then no one will know, no one will benefit, and the work will be lost. You may as well not have bothered. For the world to benefit from your work, and therefore for you to benefit fully from your work, you have to make it known.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
