<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>love on knowledge base</title>
    <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/tags/love/</link>
    <description>Recent content in love on knowledge base</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 10:12:30 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kbs.murarisumit.in/tags/love/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What Is Not Love</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/what-is-not-love/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 10:12:30 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/what-is-not-love/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This youtube video(click the title, that is how bookmarks are arranged for all posts), is of Abraham Joshua Heshel Twerski, an Israeli-American Hasidic rabbi, a scion of the Chernobyl Hasidic dynasty, and a psychiatrist specializing in substance abuse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;External-love is what I&amp;rsquo;m going to give, not what I&amp;rsquo;m going to get. (This line is bit vague)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I good line that i need to keep in check is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;People make serious mistake in thinking, that you give to those who you love, and the answer is  you love to those whom you give&amp;rdquo;
His point is, if I give something to you, I have invested myself in you, since self-love is given everybody loves themselves, now that part of me has become in you, there is part of me in you that I love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing that i read long back was:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want someone to be open to you, go ask for some favour, once people have done favor they are more open to talk to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not sure if above is good advice, never understood it properly, so please try at your own risk, but that goes by the same theory mentioned in first quote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not in alignment with his ideas, sounds good though. Got similar thoughts with brahma kumaris(&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7dNPNtdaMWY&amp;amp;list=PLCE9046E85D3918D8),&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7dNPNtdaMWY&amp;amp;list=PLCE9046E85D3918D8),&lt;/a&gt; still not in agreement with it. Love if feeling(people say), which I don&amp;rsquo;t understand and not sure what this work exactly mean. Care I understand, responsibility I comprehend, but not sure of Love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reference:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Abraham_J._Twerski&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Abraham_J._Twerski&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>

