<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>decisions on knowledge base</title>
    <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/tags/decisions/</link>
    <description>Recent content in decisions on knowledge base</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 10:01:50 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kbs.murarisumit.in/tags/decisions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Decision Making Tricks</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/71cf6d3f5df8908b988630bd57c2541e/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 10:01:50 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/71cf6d3f5df8908b988630bd57c2541e/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Came to this blog from @navelism bot, which shared this &amp;ldquo;If you can&amp;rsquo;t decide, the answer is no.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So big takeaways which made to space repitition were&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;naval-ravikant-if-you-cant-decide-the-answer-is-no&#34;&gt;Naval Ravikant: If You Can&amp;rsquo;t Decide, The Answer Is No.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you cannot decide, the answer is no. And the reason is, modern society is full of options. There are tons and tons of options. We live on a planet of seven billion people, and we are connected to everybody on the internet. There are hundreds of thousands of careers available to you. There are so many choices. You’re biologically not built to realize how many choices there are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s very, very important we only say yes when we are pretty certain. You’re never going to be absolutely certain, but you’re going to be very certain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;nassim-nicholas-taleb-you-only-need-one-reason-to-do-something&#34;&gt;Nassim Nicholas Taleb: You Only Need One Reason To Do Something.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have more than one reason to do something… just don’t do it. It does not mean that one reason is better than two, just that by invoking more than one reason you are trying to convince yourself to do something. Obvious decisions (robust to error) require no more than a single reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was common theme Warren Buffet and Charlie Munger views on picking stocks. &lt;strong&gt;We only need one reason to reject, and choice should be obivious.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Stopping Vim Now</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/decisions/why-stopping-vim-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 15:15:50 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/decisions/why-stopping-vim-now/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While learning more about tools for the trade, vim was the tool that was thrown at me a lot. This tool took a long time, because I went the wrong route and was trying to use it as IDE not how it was intended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The way I started was at first, moved to config and plugin, instead of getting comfortable with vim-help, docs or core-vim without any setting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I learnt a few things here like vim-fugitive, it&amp;rsquo;s a great plugin, and alone it makes vim a treat to use. It makes my git usage very easy, staging and selecting hunks became easy for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It works well for go and python and go still once in a while, but I still have to struggle with vim to get it work for me. I tend to spend time in my vim rather than working on problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It became more evident to me when I was watching a youtube video on binary exploitation series &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3NTXFUxcKPc&amp;amp;list=PLhixgUqwRTjxglIswKp9mpkfPNfHkzyeN&amp;amp;index=7&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3NTXFUxcKPc&amp;amp;list=PLhixgUqwRTjxglIswKp9mpkfPNfHkzyeN&amp;amp;index=7&lt;/a&gt;, and came across this tool &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/radare/radare2&#34;&gt;https://github.com/radare/radare2&lt;/a&gt;. It seemed similar to vim, and I thought for beginners the tools should be secondary but playing with art is more important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found similarities with learning badminton and drawing, focus on badminton as skill was more important. Focussed more on playing badminton, picked up any badminton racket and knew badminton racket wasn&amp;rsquo;t the bottleneck, my skills were. This was very evident to me, and was completely aware of that fact. People around me were buying head-heavy rackets, branded expensive rackets, for me 5min google and found a simple racket and just worked with that, nothing more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Same went with the drawing course that I took on udemy, I just picked a simple pencil, rubber and eraser and started working on skill, instead of focusing on the tool. Instead of blue pencil and different type of pencils.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But for a job, focussing on vim, is much trouble, it does things in an odd way, you need to learn it. It&amp;rsquo;s probably good for masters but for people like where bottleneck isn&amp;rsquo;t IDE but my skills focus should be on enhancing skills rather than tools for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tools do matter to me, tmux is one fantastic tool which I&amp;rsquo;ve picked up and I love to core. It&amp;rsquo;s a beautiful tool to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I will focus more on skills, like it worked for badminton and drawing will focus on creating products and instead of fighting with the system to get things done.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>

