<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>man-of-action on knowledge base</title>
    <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/tags/man-of-action/</link>
    <description>Recent content in man-of-action on knowledge base</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 06:04:14 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kbs.murarisumit.in/tags/man-of-action/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Perception Is Reality</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/b4623554b68ff4565baac8390eee35e5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 06:04:14 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/b4623554b68ff4565baac8390eee35e5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Was writing a few posts on being a man of actions, not being scared of the future and remembering only action matters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;%7B%7B/586a1c7bfad52e25a95e1d7d9654157a/&#34;&gt;Not scared of future&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kbs.murarisumit.in/9aed16443012e51a38b0c189b58f95ab&#34;&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s Not What I Am Underneath it&amp;rsquo;s What I Do Defines Me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Excerpts from notion kbs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Confidence is the key, if you believe in you the world will believe in you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perception is reality, how people perceive you is how they behave around you and that is real, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter if their perception is an accurate depiction of you or not because it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter. People do action, real world action based on it. Hence the &lt;strong&gt;Perception is reality or Perception becomes the reality.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I learnt it the hard way, when people perceive you in a certain way and action, real actions are taken because of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What people perceive of you are from your actions, at least this is the case with me. Your thoughts are not visible out there, only your actions. You can speak of your intention, and some people may buy it but not for long. Actions are more powerful than words.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s Not What I Am Underneath it&#39;s What I Do Defines Me</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/9aed16443012e51a38b0c189b58f95ab/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 04:55:31 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/9aed16443012e51a38b0c189b58f95ab/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Have come to the conclusion that everyone sees a different movie in their head, even if they watch the same movie. It&amp;rsquo;s all in your state of your mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Used to think that what&amp;rsquo;s in head/thoughts matters but as grown up come to conclusion that &lt;strong&gt;no actions matters&lt;/strong&gt;, what you do defines you &lt;strong&gt;not just what you think&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Related quote: &lt;a href=&#34;https://kbs.murarisumit.in/586a1c7bfad52e25a95e1d7d9654157a/&#34;&gt;Never let the future disturb you&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Never Let the Future Disturb You</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/586a1c7bfad52e25a95e1d7d9654157a/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 11:41:47 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/586a1c7bfad52e25a95e1d7d9654157a/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t let your future disturb you. You will meet if you have to, with the same weapons of reason which today arm you against present&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If sometimes your future haunts you, for me personally someone close to me told a prophecy about me and it haunted me way longer than it should, hence was able to connect to it. IMO these things haunt the weak more than man of actions and yes reading does empower you against such weak thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This quote from  bhagavad geeta helps me keep on the right track, and yes evening prayers do help me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;कर्मण्येवाधिकारस्ते मा फलेषु कदाचन |
मा कर्मफलहेतुर्भूर्मा ते सङ्गोऽस्त्वकर्मणि || 47 ||&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You have a right to perform your prescribed duties&lt;/strong&gt;, but you are not entitled to the fruits of your actions. Never consider yourself to be the cause of the results of your activities, nor be attached to inaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the future haunts you, remember, that is not in your control. No worry/stress can solve it. Only things that can help you are your actions and what you choose to do. Remember the only thing that is in your control are your actions coupled with weapons/fruit of reason/बुद्धि no more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No worry can solve issues other than your actions which are in your control.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>

