<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Humans on knowledge base</title>
    <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/tags/humans/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Humans on knowledge base</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2021 19:41:27 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kbs.murarisumit.in/tags/humans/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Company Similar to East India Company</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/c5b650102aad591b71ded2fea2a20d69/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2021 19:41:27 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/c5b650102aad591b71ded2fea2a20d69/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_Fruit_Company&#34;&gt;United fruit company&lt;/a&gt;. Created railroads, port, and other infra in Central American countries for plundering them. Owning the entire supply chain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Easy to draw comparison to what &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/East_India_Company&#34;&gt;East India Company&lt;/a&gt; did in India but on the smaller scale. Not killing millions of people, but still very brutal for any human being. I see them and see Hitler and can&amp;rsquo;t differentiate between them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still can see how people think United fruit company and &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/East_India_Company&#34;&gt;East India Company&lt;/a&gt;  were the force of good. They did good for those countries they were plundering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This video also shows the side where we see how US imperialism works. How they destabilize the country. Quite an eye-opener for someone who grew up to see the USA as a sort-of force of good and democracy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perception Is Reality</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/b4623554b68ff4565baac8390eee35e5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 06:04:14 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/b4623554b68ff4565baac8390eee35e5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Was writing a few posts on being a man of actions, not being scared of the future and remembering only action matters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;%7B%7B/586a1c7bfad52e25a95e1d7d9654157a/&#34;&gt;Not scared of future&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kbs.murarisumit.in/9aed16443012e51a38b0c189b58f95ab&#34;&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s Not What I Am Underneath it&amp;rsquo;s What I Do Defines Me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Excerpts from notion kbs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Confidence is the key, if you believe in you the world will believe in you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perception is reality, how people perceive you is how they behave around you and that is real, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter if their perception is an accurate depiction of you or not because it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter. People do action, real world action based on it. Hence the &lt;strong&gt;Perception is reality or Perception becomes the reality.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I learnt it the hard way, when people perceive you in a certain way and action, real actions are taken because of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What people perceive of you are from your actions, at least this is the case with me. Your thoughts are not visible out there, only your actions. You can speak of your intention, and some people may buy it but not for long. Actions are more powerful than words.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>

