<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Www.wealest.com on knowledge base</title>
    <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/sites/www.wealest.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Www.wealest.com on knowledge base</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 10:01:50 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kbs.murarisumit.in/sites/www.wealest.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Decision Making Tricks</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/71cf6d3f5df8908b988630bd57c2541e/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 10:01:50 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/71cf6d3f5df8908b988630bd57c2541e/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Came to this blog from @navelism bot, which shared this &amp;ldquo;If you can&amp;rsquo;t decide, the answer is no.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So big takeaways which made to space repitition were&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;naval-ravikant-if-you-cant-decide-the-answer-is-no&#34;&gt;Naval Ravikant: If You Can&amp;rsquo;t Decide, The Answer Is No.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you cannot decide, the answer is no. And the reason is, modern society is full of options. There are tons and tons of options. We live on a planet of seven billion people, and we are connected to everybody on the internet. There are hundreds of thousands of careers available to you. There are so many choices. You’re biologically not built to realize how many choices there are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s very, very important we only say yes when we are pretty certain. You’re never going to be absolutely certain, but you’re going to be very certain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;nassim-nicholas-taleb-you-only-need-one-reason-to-do-something&#34;&gt;Nassim Nicholas Taleb: You Only Need One Reason To Do Something.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have more than one reason to do something… just don’t do it. It does not mean that one reason is better than two, just that by invoking more than one reason you are trying to convince yourself to do something. Obvious decisions (robust to error) require no more than a single reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was common theme Warren Buffet and Charlie Munger views on picking stocks. &lt;strong&gt;We only need one reason to reject, and choice should be obivious.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>

