<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>hn-post on knowledge base</title>
    <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/tags/hn-post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in hn-post on knowledge base</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 08:39:21 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kbs.murarisumit.in/tags/hn-post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sell Yourself, Sell Your Work</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/sell-yourself-sell-your-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 08:39:21 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/sell-yourself-sell-your-work/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;few-notes&#34;&gt;Few notes&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doing technically brilliant work may be enough for your personal gratification, but you should never think it&amp;rsquo;s enough. If you lock yourself in a room and do the most marvellous work but don&amp;rsquo;t tell anyone, then no one will know, no one will benefit, and the work will be lost. You may as well not have bothered. For the world to benefit from your work, and therefore for you to benefit fully from your work, you have to make it known.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;commentry&#34;&gt;Commentry&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Peter Thiel has an interesting take on sales in his book Zero to One. He makes the case that good selling and good teaching are pretty much the same thing. The best teachers know how to sell the topic they teach&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;personal-opinion&#34;&gt;Personal opinion&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The way i take it is, here it&amp;rsquo;s more about communicating well and and informing people about work you do, which is important imo too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something like Dropbox YC post: &lt;a href=&#34;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=8863&#34;&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=8863&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Linus post on usenet for his little kernel that he created.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m doing a (free) operating system (just a hobby, won&amp;rsquo;t be big and professional like gnu) for 386(486) AT clones. This has been brewing since April, and is starting to get ready. I&amp;rsquo;d like any feedback on things people like/dislike in minix, as my OS resembles it somewhat (same physical layout of the file-system (due to practical reasons) among other things). I&amp;rsquo;ve currently ported bash(1.08) and gcc(1.40), and things seem to work. This implies that I&amp;rsquo;ll get something practical within a few months [&amp;hellip;] Yes - it&amp;rsquo;s free of any minix code, and it has a multi-threaded fs. It is NOT portable (uses 386 task switching etc), and it probably never will support anything other than AT-harddisks, as that&amp;rsquo;s all I have :-(.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For good work, one should communicate and inform it with people around him.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>

