<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>murarisumit on knowledge base</title>
    <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/author/murarisumit/</link>
    <description>Recent content in murarisumit on knowledge base</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 11:50:41 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kbs.murarisumit.in/author/murarisumit/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sharingbuttons</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/sharingbuttons.io/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 11:50:41 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/sharingbuttons.io/</guid>
      <description>Not sure how reached here, wasn&amp;rsquo;t actively looking for it but glad found it. Not a fan of bulky tracking websites, so this social little privacy-centric media buttons for someone and myself to share work with poeple on various network.
Not a fan of twitter, but using twitter to reach out to people get feedback, improve ourselves, make myself better and this note is to remind myself why enabled this feature of social sharing in this site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>India&#39;s Maiden Indigenous Aircraft Carrier</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/india-maiden-indigenous-aircraft-carrier/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 22:48:36 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/india-maiden-indigenous-aircraft-carrier/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s is good to see fellow country man are working are making things are aircraft carrier, weighing 40000 tonnes in itself looks like huge engineering and manufacturing feat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homelabs Setup</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/homelabs-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 22:24:23 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/homelabs-setup/</guid>
      <description>For sometime having ideas of using homelabs, found this guide useful but have other important priorities right now. Hence parking it here for future referece.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bigger Impact of Distraction More Than Just Time Lost</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/bigger-impact-for-distraction-more-than-just-time-lost/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 09:48:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/bigger-impact-for-distraction-more-than-just-time-lost/</guid>
      <description>Somehow reached to this tacky/clickbaity title &amp;ldquo;How the smartphone is destroying you from inside&amp;rdquo; https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4HjC245ugW8. Probably from the past few days, putting my head to these distractions. They seem to me like modern day alcoholic drinks. You enjoy it and forget your problems, similar promises made by alcoholic drinks.
So the point video makes is, the time we invest in these addictive systems(there whole KPI is to make stay people on their website) is anyways gone, but there are more far reaching impact because of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finally Some Sense in Laptops</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/finally-some-sense-in-laptops/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 09:44:42 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/finally-some-sense-in-laptops/</guid>
      <description>It was good to see nice laptops coming in now. Which have this repairability in mind. This laptop specially looks with it&amp;rsquo;s modularity. As iFixit says, this is slippery slope, we have seen many such initiatives come and go. So hoping this works time and changes consumer electronics industry for good.
Kudos to https://frame.work/ team.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
