<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Network on knowledge base</title><link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/tags/network/</link><description>Recent content in Network on knowledge base</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 09:24:33 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kbs.murarisumit.in/tags/network/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>IPv4 Link Local</title><link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/tils/ipv4-link-local/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 09:24:33 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/tils/ipv4-link-local/</guid><description>&lt;p>To participate in wide-area IP networking, a host needs to be
configured with IP addresses for its interfaces, either manually by
the user or automatically from a source on the network such as a
Dynamic Host Configuration Protocol (DHCP) server. Unfortunately,
such address configuration information may not always be available.
It is therefore beneficial for a host to be able to depend on a
useful subset of IP networking functions even when no address
configuration is available.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It means link-local address are used when host is not able to get any network configuration from&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Manual Configuration&lt;/li>
&lt;li>DHCP (DHCPv4 or DHCPv6)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>then it automatically take IP from pool of &lt;code>169.254.0.0/16 (169.254.0.0 – 169.254.255.255)&lt;/code>
mentioned in RFC &lt;a href="https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc3927">3927&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Process:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Take any random IP from above pool&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Check if IP is not taken by others using broadcast via ARP&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If IP is taken then go back to step 1&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If IP is not taken, then assign the IP to yourself and be ready for networking.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Important points to be noted&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>These address are not routable by router
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Why : Because it&amp;rsquo;s in RFC, our rulebook for internet and also rule makes sense too.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In step2, we only check in our ARP domain i.e. layer 2, it makes sense not to get these routed by layer3, since there is bright chance other machines in their layer 2 would&amp;rsquo;ve done the same and IP would conflict.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>Reference:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>RFC &lt;a href="https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc3927">3927&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>