<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>life-goals on knowledge base</title>
    <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/tags/life-goals/</link>
    <description>Recent content in life-goals on knowledge base</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2021 03:02:45 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kbs.murarisumit.in/tags/life-goals/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Price of Becoming EXCEPTIONAL in Life Jordan Peterson Motivation</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/6347fd23beb0ba39c9b52a4dfd7c7ca5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2021 03:02:45 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/6347fd23beb0ba39c9b52a4dfd7c7ca5/</guid>
      <description>Wrote a note on Jordan-Peterson-Successful-Men-Are-Insane-And-Work-All-The-Time yesterday, and found similar video on the same topic. So youtube recommendation is smart, and I&amp;rsquo;m not the only one who made to stupid( like it though) conclusion.
I&amp;rsquo;m ready to give that price, and become exceptional. Family do matter to me, friends to matter to me, but would keep the circle small and would focus on the goals that I have. Ready to give 80 hours work-week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jordan Peterson Successful Men Are Insane and Work All the Time</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/ce39966c39f2ea7d1a55946669a84685/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Aug 2021 01:51:32 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/ce39966c39f2ea7d1a55946669a84685/</guid>
      <description>He said in one of his interviews that men wrote to him and told that he changed his life. I&amp;rsquo;m one of such characters. Here also a lot of thanks goes to people who made the internet happen, so I could watch his lessons/lectures or speeches.
To achieve to be highly successful in corporate world i.e. reach at high position in social order one has to put insane amount of work, he mentioned 80 hours work week, translates to ~ 12 hours every day without breaks for years and with focus and determination.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
