<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>youtube on knowledge base</title>
    <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/tags/youtube/</link>
    <description>Recent content in youtube on knowledge base</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 06:04:14 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kbs.murarisumit.in/tags/youtube/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Perception Is Reality</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/b4623554b68ff4565baac8390eee35e5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 06:04:14 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/b4623554b68ff4565baac8390eee35e5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Was writing a few posts on being a man of actions, not being scared of the future and remembering only action matters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;%7B%7B/586a1c7bfad52e25a95e1d7d9654157a/&#34;&gt;Not scared of future&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://kbs.murarisumit.in/9aed16443012e51a38b0c189b58f95ab&#34;&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s Not What I Am Underneath it&amp;rsquo;s What I Do Defines Me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Excerpts from notion kbs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Confidence is the key, if you believe in you the world will believe in you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perception is reality, how people perceive you is how they behave around you and that is real, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter if their perception is an accurate depiction of you or not because it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter. People do action, real world action based on it. Hence the &lt;strong&gt;Perception is reality or Perception becomes the reality.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I learnt it the hard way, when people perceive you in a certain way and action, real actions are taken because of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What people perceive of you are from your actions, at least this is the case with me. Your thoughts are not visible out there, only your actions. You can speak of your intention, and some people may buy it but not for long. Actions are more powerful than words.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Dark Knight Rises the Climb Scene</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/82f13670d5d8ce84febcb23889eea474/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 03:35:52 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/82f13670d5d8ce84febcb23889eea474/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One more youtube video, batman this time. This scene might have given goose bumps to Roger Federer too, you may fall but it&amp;rsquo;s what you choose afterwards that matters the most.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also the dialogue from rocky comes to my mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It ain&amp;rsquo;t about how hard you hit; It&amp;rsquo;s about how hard you can get hit and keep moving forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American nationalism had brought beautiful movies out there and something to learn from. Deserters/Refugees coming from every parts of world and joining together and making a &lt;strong&gt;great&lt;/strong&gt; nation. Nation making is huge task, India still isn&amp;rsquo;t a nation yet despite such commonality, history and culture, but American built nation from deserters, some refugees true but most deserters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Always in awe to see to see American might and what they have achieved. They really are a nation to look upto.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Living With the Dark Winters in Sweden Midnight Sun and Polar Night</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/cf319bbe3527ea414ff169110c93221f/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 02:02:39 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/cf319bbe3527ea414ff169110c93221f/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Beautiful videography done and soothing music and voice. These video make me appreciate the country I live in.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pouring Molten Metal Inside a Seashell WHAT HAPPENS Experimental Metal Casting at Home DIY</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/49a1162eb90beacee617cdce3de7bbaf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 10:55:23 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/49a1162eb90beacee617cdce3de7bbaf/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is beautiful, how crafted the nature is and amazed at human intelligence who think they know more that nature itself and try to change it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Price of Becoming EXCEPTIONAL in Life Jordan Peterson Motivation</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/6347fd23beb0ba39c9b52a4dfd7c7ca5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2021 03:02:45 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/6347fd23beb0ba39c9b52a4dfd7c7ca5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Wrote a note on &lt;a href=&#34;https://kbs.murarisumit.in/ce39966c39f2ea7d1a55946669a84685/&#34;&gt;Jordan-Peterson-Successful-Men-Are-Insane-And-Work-All-The-Time&lt;/a&gt; yesterday, and found similar video on the same topic. So youtube recommendation is smart, and I&amp;rsquo;m not the only one who made to stupid( like it though) conclusion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m ready to give that price, and become exceptional. Family do matter to me, friends to matter to me, but would keep the circle small and would focus on the goals that I have. Ready to give 80 hours work-week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goals are private for now, but for my reference are kept at: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.notion.so/yinyangi/a-lifetime-11c407f3b4034e14805328f1c7bd5ffa&#34;&gt;https://www.notion.so/yinyangi/a-lifetime-11c407f3b4034e14805328f1c7bd5ffa&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Novak Djokovic vs Roger Federer Wimbledon 2019 FullMatch</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/3eea4986a87740003aa7e5b40354ce03/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Aug 2021 04:57:43 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/3eea4986a87740003aa7e5b40354ce03/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One more djo&amp;rsquo;s match, but was looking at federer who showed his metal at 36 yrs of age.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Novak Djokovic vs Rafael Nadal in the Longest Final in Grand Slam History</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/dba141a324349154865a7bdf421eee15/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Aug 2021 01:48:05 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/dba141a324349154865a7bdf421eee15/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If this can&amp;rsquo;t inspire anyone, not sure what could. These guys played for around ~ 6 hours, and that&amp;rsquo;s an incredible feat of achievement.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nithin Kamath of Zerodha Says True Financial Freedom Is About Acquiring Skills First Than Money</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/60cdd644ced2abd406c37a892f8386e3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 23:41:17 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/60cdd644ced2abd406c37a892f8386e3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This guy is simple to understand, no out of the world quotations. Can relate to him, seems like a neighbourhood elder brother(bhaiya) who you can talk to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What he mentioned was, spend on skills. More like one message in a 3-idiot movie. Run after excellence, success will come to you. He isn&amp;rsquo;t sadhu and adds on to say to buy material assets like cars or houses. If a house gives peace of mind, improves quality of life, go buy a house. If cars make your life easy, use it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another important thing he mentioned is, we have to make money work for us to be financially independent and financial freedom is about being content. There are endless materialistic traps.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Engine Works</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/1125b6a1a9edde68c82b00c6e62a2f2e/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 04:33:09 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/1125b6a1a9edde68c82b00c6e62a2f2e/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Beautiful things, always read 4 strokes work, but seeing this video(click title to go to video) gave so much more clarity and satisfaction. Now would be comfortable to say that,  i have good theoretical understanding of how engines work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Suprising Genius of 3D Printing Rockets</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/15a46dccb293a270265ac2a53d3fd332/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 21:53:06 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/15a46dccb293a270265ac2a53d3fd332/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;3D printing is in nascent stages India, but seeing rocket being made out of this tech is so motivating and makes you look in future about possibility and how would it look like. Also thoughts come to mind, that why aren&amp;rsquo;t thing like electric 2-wheelers, drones, houses in India are using it, but then answer comes even more quickly, that people like are in jobs instead of innovating out there, so how would the change happen.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leadership Lecture Sam Manekshaw</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/leadership-lecture-field-marshall-sam-mannekshaw/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 09:41:06 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/leadership-lecture-field-marshall-sam-mannekshaw/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;He believes leaders are not born, you can make a leaders out of man with reasonable common-sense and decency and rest of portion he then mentions attributes of leadership.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of part is taken from summarized transcript by fellow youtuber at video with little changes from my side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;according-to-manekshaw-sir-qualities-of-leader&#34;&gt;According to manekshaw sir qualities of leader&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Professional competence&lt;/strong&gt; :
He provided example of Defence Minister who had no idea about howitzer, motor etc how can he lead the army officers !!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ability to take a decision and take a full responsibility for it&lt;/strong&gt; :
👉🏻 act of omission is much worse than act of commission of wrong.
👉🏻 why a person don&amp;rsquo;t take decision?? because he lacks confidence!! why?  because he lacks professional knowledge !
👉🏻 if you must be a bloody fool be must quickly - manekshawism&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Absolute justice and impartiality&lt;/strong&gt;
By this way you may not be liked by all but be respected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Courage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;👉🏻 moral courage:  ability to distinguish right from wrong and standby it irrespective of what others think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;👉🏻 yes man, is horrible man, he may rise very high, but will never become leader, he will be used by superior and disliked by colleagues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;👉🏻(he mentioned story, when he was summoned, during east Pakistan crisis, by Indira Gandhi and other cabinet minister who expected him to be agree to intervene in april month, which was not prudent and he boldly put forward his dissent about choice of time rather than being yesman )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;👉🏻 physical courage:
Everyone is scared, he tells he was scared too. To be a leader, one to have to physical courageous in face of adversity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He mentioned a story, where his subordinate threatened that he would kill him, that chap was big but he despite being scared. He made him santri for night and asked him to bring tea and hot water to him in morning. He had option to have more security around him, but he showed he has courage and also showing trust in his men. Funnily he goes on to say, don&amp;rsquo;t be fool-hardy like he was but we need to understand the idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;5&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Loyalty&lt;/strong&gt;
Its two way thing, one can rightfully demand it from subordinate if he is also loyal to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Management of men and sources&lt;/strong&gt;
He mostly conveyed about role of emotional intelligence, that human have problems so being stern should be combined with human touch and sense of humour play a great role in it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Discipline and Character&lt;/strong&gt;
No amount leadership would put things right, the two other important aspect(that we usually lack)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;👉🏻Discipline&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discipline is code of conduct for decent living in society one with the other
This code of conduct has come from generation to generation, it&amp;rsquo;s come from holy books and refined on as cultures change&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Example: Non-punctuality is an act of ill-discipline. Very harmful for society and nation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;👉🏻 Character&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should be honest, truthful etc. The big picture is, &lt;strong&gt;knowing what you are&lt;/strong&gt;, not let fans or hangers-on put you on pedestals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do watch the video, if you have time. You can learn lessons on how to communicates and sweet little jokes he cracks, which make it far insightful then above mentioned transcript&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understand Electricity Generation</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/understand-electricity-generation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 18:40:36 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/understand-electricity-generation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This video actually helps us understand how electricity is generated by using magnets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When studies electricity for first time, never understood where does frequency mean, what current is, what does voltage mean and simple things like this and whole electrical energy didn&amp;rsquo;t made sense to me. Now most of it does, probably if I go for advanced study would really make sense.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lin Dan vs Lee Chong Wei</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/lindan-vs-leechongwei/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 23:44:26 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/lindan-vs-leechongwei/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Seeing them together, playing with such skills is so beautiful. Love their game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great video compilation too.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bigger Impact of Distraction More Than Just Time Lost</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/bigger-impact-for-distraction-more-than-just-time-lost/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 09:48:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/bigger-impact-for-distraction-more-than-just-time-lost/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Somehow reached to this tacky/clickbaity title &amp;ldquo;How the smartphone is destroying you from inside&amp;rdquo; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4HjC245ugW8&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4HjC245ugW8&lt;/a&gt;. Probably from the past few days, putting my head to these distractions. They seem to me like modern day alcoholic drinks. You enjoy it and forget your problems, similar promises made by alcoholic drinks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the point video makes is, the time we invest in these addictive systems(there whole KPI is to make stay people on their website) is anyways gone, but there are more far reaching impact because of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because of distraction, you actually context switch from one task to other, which lower your focus on work you&amp;rsquo;re doing or we can say one is not able to deliver to our fullest potential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we aren&amp;rsquo;t able to deliver our fullest potential, psychological effect like anxiety, distress chip in, which are far more disastrous for short and long term.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It also starts a vicious cycle, the more anxiety and distress we feel the more we go for these distractions. In the short-term we don&amp;rsquo;t see problems, we play games, enjoy movies, adore photos, but the problem doesn&amp;rsquo;t go away. Problems are still there, and we have even less time to solve them than before. This is a far more powerful/dangerous enemy than smoke ever was, because we don&amp;rsquo;t even need to go shop for this, it&amp;rsquo;s at our smartphone, just next to us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This continuous loop, then reduces our ability to focus and concentrate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;solution&#34;&gt;Solution&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the problem is defined and  most of us are aware of it and we need solutions. One such technique if you have lower focus time is to use pomodoro technique, created by Francesco Cirillo in the late 1980s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Short note on pomodoro technique which helps me&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix tasks you want to work on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work in done is this timebox manner: &lt;strong&gt;loop(25 - 5 - 25 - 5 - 25 - 5 - 25 - 15 )&lt;/strong&gt; OR &lt;strong&gt;loop(25 - 5 - 25 - 5 - 25 - 15-)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Focus work for 25 mins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take 5 mins break, no phones here, usually a little walk, sometimes water and relax at times&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Continue this for 3 times.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take a longer break for the 4th time. Continue and repeat.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reference&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pomodoro_Technique&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pomodoro_Technique&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/small-distractions-can-have-big-consequences/&#34;&gt;https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/small-distractions-can-have-big-consequences/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.frontiersin.org/articles/10.3389/fpsyg.2014.00841/full&#34;&gt;https://www.frontiersin.org/articles/10.3389/fpsyg.2014.00841/full&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.frontiersin.org/articles/10.3389/fpsyg.2014.00439/full&#34;&gt;https://www.frontiersin.org/articles/10.3389/fpsyg.2014.00439/full&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finally Some Sense in Laptops</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/finally-some-sense-in-laptops/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 09:44:42 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/finally-some-sense-in-laptops/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It was good to see nice laptops coming in now. Which have this repairability in mind. This laptop specially looks with it&amp;rsquo;s modularity. As iFixit says, this is slippery slope, we have seen many such initiatives come and go. So hoping this company works and changes consumer electronics industry for good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kudos to &lt;a href=&#34;https://frame.work/&#34;&gt;https://frame.work/&lt;/a&gt; team.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is Not Love</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/what-is-not-love/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 10:12:30 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/what-is-not-love/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This youtube video(click the title, that is how bookmarks are arranged for all posts), is of Abraham Joshua Heshel Twerski, an Israeli-American Hasidic rabbi, a scion of the Chernobyl Hasidic dynasty, and a psychiatrist specializing in substance abuse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;External-love is what I&amp;rsquo;m going to give, not what I&amp;rsquo;m going to get. (This line is bit vague)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I good line that i need to keep in check is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;People make serious mistake in thinking, that you give to those who you love, and the answer is  you love to those whom you give&amp;rdquo;
His point is, if I give something to you, I have invested myself in you, since self-love is given everybody loves themselves, now that part of me has become in you, there is part of me in you that I love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing that i read long back was:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want someone to be open to you, go ask for some favour, once people have done favor they are more open to talk to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not sure if above is good advice, never understood it properly, so please try at your own risk, but that goes by the same theory mentioned in first quote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not in alignment with his ideas, sounds good though. Got similar thoughts with brahma kumaris(&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7dNPNtdaMWY&amp;amp;list=PLCE9046E85D3918D8),&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7dNPNtdaMWY&amp;amp;list=PLCE9046E85D3918D8),&lt;/a&gt; still not in agreement with it. Love if feeling(people say), which I don&amp;rsquo;t understand and not sure what this work exactly mean. Care I understand, responsibility I comprehend, but not sure of Love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reference:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Abraham_J._Twerski&#34;&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Abraham_J._Twerski&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flamenco Street Music</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/flamenco-street-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 14:57:34 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/flamenco-street-music/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Was listening to thismusic in college, today there was discussion and flamenco again came up. It was sweet memory lane to go and also happy to see this video is still there in youtube.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How intrusive youtube-ads are, but is does provide value of society. Not sure if we have any way to store music forever like we have books for text.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linus Interview Linuxcon North America 2016</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/linus-interview-linuxcon-north-america-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 17:05:47 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/linus-interview-linuxcon-north-america-2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Linus interviews are always fun to watch. One of favorite past-time activity for me. Loved watching it. Keeping them here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One good comment mentioned one simple/funny thing in interview&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in early MVP version of linux the disk sectors were hard coded&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Lithium-ion Battery Work</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/how-litihium-ion-battery-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 22:26:21 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/how-litihium-ion-battery-work/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;He says that it&amp;rsquo;s better not to discarge battery completely, better to charge when it&amp;rsquo;s at 30-40%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additional youtube video how batteries are manufactured&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How SSD Work</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/how-ssd-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 16:24:45 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/how-ssd-work/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ctfs Are Awesome</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/ctfs-are-awesome/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 07:01:13 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/ctfs-are-awesome/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>

