<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>youtube on knowledge base</title>
    <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/tags/youtube/</link>
    <description>Recent content in youtube on knowledge base</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 04:33:09 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kbs.murarisumit.in/tags/youtube/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How Engine Works</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/1125b6a1a9edde68c82b00c6e62a2f2e/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 04:33:09 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/1125b6a1a9edde68c82b00c6e62a2f2e/</guid>
      <description>Beautiful things, always read 4 strokes work, but seeing this video(click title to go to video) gave so much more clarity and satisfaction. Now would be comfortable to say that, i have good theoretical understanding of how engines work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Suprising Genius of 3D Printing Rockets</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/15a46dccb293a270265ac2a53d3fd332/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 21:53:06 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/15a46dccb293a270265ac2a53d3fd332/</guid>
      <description>3D printing is in nascent stages India, but seeing rocket being made out of this tech is so motivating and makes you look in future about possibility and how would it look like. Also thoughts come to mind, that why aren&amp;rsquo;t thing like electric 2-wheelers, drones, houses in India are using it, but then answer comes even more quickly, that people like are in jobs instead of innovating out there, so how would the change happen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leadership Lecture Sam Manekshaw</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/leadership-lecture-field-marshall-sam-mannekshaw/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 09:41:06 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/leadership-lecture-field-marshall-sam-mannekshaw/</guid>
      <description>He believes leaders are not born, you can make a leaders out of man with reasonable common-sense and decency and rest of portion he then mentions attributes of leadership.
Most of part is taken from summarized transcript by fellow youtuber at video with little changes from my side.
According to manekshaw sir qualities of leader   Professional competence : He provided example of Defence Minister who had no idea about howitzer, motor etc how can he lead the army officers !</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understand Electricity Generation</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/understand-electricity-generation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 18:40:36 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/understand-electricity-generation/</guid>
      <description>This video actually helps us understand how electricity is generated by using magnets.
When studies electricity for first time, never understood where does frequency mean, what current is, what does voltage mean and simple things like this and whole electrical energy didn&amp;rsquo;t made sense to me. Now most of it does, probably if I go for advanced study would really make sense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lin Dan vs Lee Chong Wei</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/lindan-vs-leechongwei/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 23:44:26 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/lindan-vs-leechongwei/</guid>
      <description>Seeing them together, playing with such skills is so beautiful. Love their game.
Great video compilation too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bigger Impact of Distraction More Than Just Time Lost</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/bigger-impact-for-distraction-more-than-just-time-lost/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 09:48:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/bigger-impact-for-distraction-more-than-just-time-lost/</guid>
      <description>Somehow reached to this tacky/clickbaity title &amp;ldquo;How the smartphone is destroying you from inside&amp;rdquo; https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4HjC245ugW8. Probably from the past few days, putting my head to these distractions. They seem to me like modern day alcoholic drinks. You enjoy it and forget your problems, similar promises made by alcoholic drinks.
So the point video makes is, the time we invest in these addictive systems(there whole KPI is to make stay people on their website) is anyways gone, but there are more far reaching impact because of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finally Some Sense in Laptops</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/finally-some-sense-in-laptops/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 09:44:42 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/finally-some-sense-in-laptops/</guid>
      <description>It was good to see nice laptops coming in now. Which have this repairability in mind. This laptop specially looks with it&amp;rsquo;s modularity. As iFixit says, this is slippery slope, we have seen many such initiatives come and go. So hoping this company works and changes consumer electronics industry for good.
Kudos to https://frame.work/ team.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is Not Love</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/what-is-not-love/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 10:12:30 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/what-is-not-love/</guid>
      <description>This youtube video(click the title, that is how bookmarks are arranged for all posts), is of Abraham Joshua Heshel Twerski, an Israeli-American Hasidic rabbi, a scion of the Chernobyl Hasidic dynasty, and a psychiatrist specializing in substance abuse.
External-love is what I&amp;rsquo;m going to give, not what I&amp;rsquo;m going to get. (This line is bit vague)
I good line that i need to keep in check is:
 &amp;ldquo;People make serious mistake in thinking, that you give to those who you love, and the answer is you love to those whom you give&amp;rdquo; His point is, if I give something to you, I have invested myself in you, since self-love is given everybody loves themselves, now that part of me has become in you, there is part of me in you that I love.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flamenco Street Music</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/flamenco-street-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 14:57:34 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/flamenco-street-music/</guid>
      <description>Was listening to thismusic in college, today there was discussion and flamenco again came up. It was sweet memory lane to go and also happy to see this video is still there in youtube.
How intrusive youtube-ads are, but is does provide value of society. Not sure if we have any way to store music forever like we have books for text.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linus Interview Linuxcon North America 2016</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/linus-interview-linuxcon-north-america-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 17:05:47 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/linus-interview-linuxcon-north-america-2016/</guid>
      <description>Linus interviews are always fun to watch. One of favorite past-time activity for me. Loved watching it. Keeping them here.
One good comment mentioned one simple/funny thing in interview
 in early MVP version of linux the disk sectors were hard coded
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Lithium-ion Battery Work</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/how-litihium-ion-battery-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 22:26:21 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/how-litihium-ion-battery-work/</guid>
      <description>He says that it&amp;rsquo;s better not to discarge battery completely, better to charge when it&amp;rsquo;s at 30-40%.
Additional youtube video how batteries are manufactured</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How SSD Work</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/how-ssd-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 16:24:45 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/how-ssd-work/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ctfs Are Awesome</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/ctfs-are-awesome/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 07:01:13 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/ctfs-are-awesome/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
