<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2021-08 on knowledge base</title>
    <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/month/2021-08/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2021-08 on knowledge base</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 04:57:32 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kbs.murarisumit.in/month/2021-08/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How Kubectl Logs Work</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/d19e8438d682f3f5a897296206ca9828/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 04:57:32 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/d19e8438d682f3f5a897296206ca9828/</guid>
      <description>Links to notion page, as it had diagram and it was easier to put post like these on notion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hard Drive Failure Report Backblaze</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/332d6b43914e2eeba6333c1a057f9f15/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 04:45:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/332d6b43914e2eeba6333c1a057f9f15/</guid>
      <description>It gives us of which hard drive to buy and which not as they are one of the biggest buyer of hard-driver and see those working at scale.
As they mentioned Seagate ST16000NM001G has quite a high failure rate of 6.72% with backblaze so it would be wise to not buy that hard-drive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fake Reviews in Amazon</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/203914e598a6b162307c47a51eb79378/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 04:41:18 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/203914e598a6b162307c47a51eb79378/</guid>
      <description>OP post from reddit thread  First of all my background - I&#39;ve been working on Amazon for years and know all the tricks of getting ranked. I do not engage in black hat tactics and I did the review game when it wasnt against TOS. As soon as they changed everything, I did not engage. However because of all my contacts I&#39;m in the know for a lot of things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Engine Works</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/1125b6a1a9edde68c82b00c6e62a2f2e/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 04:33:09 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/1125b6a1a9edde68c82b00c6e62a2f2e/</guid>
      <description>Beautiful things, always read 4 strokes work, but seeing this video(click title to go to video) gave so much more clarity and satisfaction. Now would be comfortable to say that, i have good theoretical understanding of how engines work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Suprising Genius of 3D Printing Rockets</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/15a46dccb293a270265ac2a53d3fd332/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 21:53:06 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/15a46dccb293a270265ac2a53d3fd332/</guid>
      <description>3D printing is in nascent stages India, but seeing rocket being made out of this tech is so motivating and makes you look in future about possibility and how would it look like. Also thoughts come to mind, that why aren&amp;rsquo;t thing like electric 2-wheelers, drones, houses in India are using it, but then answer comes even more quickly, that people like are in jobs instead of innovating out there, so how would the change happen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving From Human Friendly Urls to Ugly Uuid</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/c0e91193f16d7899b44017706767cfb1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 17:29:07 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/c0e91193f16d7899b44017706767cfb1/</guid>
      <description>Human friendly url
Advantage:
 Easy for human to read(obivious) Probably better for search engines to get results(who know anyways, it would make sense having URL as params to search result imo)  Disadvantage:
 Values have to fixed, not modification(important for me).  Still structure are not fixed for me, so don&amp;rsquo;t want to tie myself with title or path or director.   Cross-referencing become difficult  Cross referencing is important to me, and with keeping other param than UUID would be difficult to maintain, as it might break URL on this website(which is last thing I want), hence opting to machine generated unique ID from hugo i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Container Security Nist 800 190</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/container-security-nist-800-190/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 10:17:05 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/container-security-nist-800-190/</guid>
      <description>About link takes you to NIST(National Institute of Standards and Technology) guide for container security @ https://nvlpubs.nist.gov/nistpubs/SpecialPublications/NIST.SP.800-190.pdf</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux Load Avgs</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/linux-load-avgs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 09:25:45 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/linux-load-avgs/</guid>
      <description>Excerpt from blog post Linux load averages are &amp;ldquo;system load averages&amp;rdquo; that show the running thread (task) demand on the system as an average number of running plus waiting threads. This measures demand, which can be greater than what the system is currently processing. Most tools show three averages, for 1, 5, and 15 minutes:
Some interpretations:
 If the averages are 0.0, then your system is idle. If the 1 minute average is higher than the 5 or 15 minute averages, then load is increasing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>K8s Failure Stories</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/k8s-failure-stories/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 00:37:09 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/k8s-failure-stories/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Awesome Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/awesome-kubernetes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 00:16:59 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/awesome-kubernetes/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Awesome Docker Compose</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/awesome-docker-compose/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 00:16:18 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/awesome-docker-compose/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solar System if Moon Was Only One Pixel</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/solar-system-if-moon-was-only-one-pixel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Aug 2021 23:50:34 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/solar-system-if-moon-was-only-one-pixel/</guid>
      <description>Saw this visualization long-back and was storing things up here(https://www.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/), now moving them up here now. Yes, there is lot of empty space in universe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understand Electricity Generation</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/understand-electricity-generation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 18:40:36 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/understand-electricity-generation/</guid>
      <description>This video actually helps us understand how electricity is generated by using magnets.
When studies electricity for first time, never understood where does frequency mean, what current is, what does voltage mean and simple things like this and whole electrical energy didn&amp;rsquo;t made sense to me. Now most of it does, probably if I go for advanced study would really make sense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kuberentes Kbrew</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/k8s-kbrew/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 13:33:47 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/k8s-kbrew/</guid>
      <description>This tool looks good, and love the ease of this. It&amp;rsquo;s easy way to deploy the applications over cluster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Awesome K8s Security</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/awesome-k8s-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 12:50:34 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/awesome-k8s-security/</guid>
      <description>A curated list for Kubernetes (K8s) Security resources such as articles, books, tools, talks and videos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sharingbuttons</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/sharingbuttons.io/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 11:50:41 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/sharingbuttons.io/</guid>
      <description>Not sure how reached here, wasn&amp;rsquo;t actively looking for it but glad found it. Not a fan of bulky tracking websites, so this social little privacy-centric media buttons for reader and myself make ton of sense to me.
Not a fan of twitter, but using twitter to reach out to people get feedback, improve ourselves, make myself better and this note is to remind myself why enabled this feature of social sharing in this site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo Good Archive Page</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/hugo-good-archive-page/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 09:39:45 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/hugo-good-archive-page/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s good archive page style, save time and easy navigation for website. Intent is to make archive page like this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayes Rule and Medical Tests</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/bayes-rule-medical-tests/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 08:54:42 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/bayes-rule-medical-tests/</guid>
      <description>All medical tests do is update their probability of having disease, and not tell if we have disease or not.
There are three things
 Prevalence : How common is that disease around here? What chance of having it without tests? Sensitivity : If even disease is present, how good is the test at detecting it. Specificity : If a test is taken, there can be other issues that result. Clots in the pancreas can be because of a lot many things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trust Your Instincts Instead of Hearsay</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/tils/trust-your-instincts-instead-of-hearsay/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 02:33:04 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/tils/trust-your-instincts-instead-of-hearsay/</guid>
      <description>More my understanding of the world grows by reading various prophecies people have made before, makes me realize that there is no point in taking hearsay seriously, be it from news channels, be it anywhere else. No one knows the future, it&amp;rsquo;s so obvious, still people are into prediction/criticism business and it&amp;rsquo;s working well too.
 In 1909 Washington Post wrote &amp;ldquo;There will never be such a thing as commercial aerial freighters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>India&#39;s Maiden Indigenous Aircraft Carrier</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/india-maiden-indigenous-aircraft-carrier/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 22:48:36 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/india-maiden-indigenous-aircraft-carrier/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s is good to see fellow country man are working are making things are aircraft carrier, weighing 40000 tonnes in itself looks like huge engineering and manufacturing feat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homelabs Setup</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/homelabs-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 22:24:23 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/homelabs-setup/</guid>
      <description>For sometime having ideas of using homelabs, found this guide useful but have other important priorities right now. Hence parking it here for future referece.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bigger Impact of Distraction More Than Just Time Lost</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/bigger-impact-for-distraction-more-than-just-time-lost/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 09:48:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/bigger-impact-for-distraction-more-than-just-time-lost/</guid>
      <description>Somehow reached to this tacky/clickbaity title &amp;ldquo;How the smartphone is destroying you from inside&amp;rdquo; https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4HjC245ugW8. Probably from the past few days, putting my head to these distractions. They seem to me like modern day alcoholic drinks. You enjoy it and forget your problems, similar promises made by alcoholic drinks.
So the point video makes is, the time we invest in these addictive systems(there whole KPI is to make stay people on their website) is anyways gone, but there are more far reaching impact because of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finally Some Sense in Laptops</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/finally-some-sense-in-laptops/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 09:44:42 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/bookmarks/finally-some-sense-in-laptops/</guid>
      <description>It was good to see nice laptops coming in now. Which have this repairability in mind. This laptop specially looks with it&amp;rsquo;s modularity. As iFixit says, this is slippery slope, we have seen many such initiatives come and go. So hoping this company works and changes consumer electronics industry for good.
Kudos to https://frame.work/ team.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
