<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tils on knowledge base</title>
    <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/tils/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tils on knowledge base</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 12:17:11 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kbs.murarisumit.in/tils/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Moments: Breakfast With Champions</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/tils/moments-breakfast-with-champions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 12:17:11 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/tils/moments-breakfast-with-champions/</guid>
      <description>Hayden: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cfksYTFzY5M Point is made was cricket was a big threatre for him, and live broadcasted threatre. He gave his performance and fine. I didn&amp;rsquo;t saw cricket or any game on those lines before. He made it feel like art form.
Brett Lee: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Hl0Wc6TaokI&amp;amp;t Pain brett lee went through while bowling:
 https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Hl0Wc6TaokI&amp;amp;t=14m0s https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Hl0Wc6TaokI&amp;amp;t=15m26s  Michael Holding: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fbKkJO1OEc4 Really nice to hear his opinion and found someone who synchronizes with my thought process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abrahamic History, Lengend and Mythology</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/tils/abrahamic-history-lengend-mythology/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 02:37:08 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/tils/abrahamic-history-lengend-mythology/</guid>
      <description>There is set of religions that come from Abrahim. I was trying to understand how they all are related.
There are three abrahamic religions
 Judaism Christanity Islam  Q: Who is Abrahim(Ibrahim in quran) ?
 Abraham (18th century BCE), tenth-generation descendant of Noah, of Hebrew lineage, was the son of Terah, uncle of Lot, father of Isaac, grandfather of Jacob, and forefather of the Israelites. Jewish tradition states that he was the first to actively spread belief in One God  Q: Who is Noah ?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CSS id vs class</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/tils/css-id-vs-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 13:42:43 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/tils/css-id-vs-class/</guid>
      <description>Simple CSS question while working on resume project, is when to use id and when to use class.
First thing to know about IDs:
 IDs are unique
 Browser knows a bit about IDs, this ID is what we see in fragment or hash-value. Browser uses this to reach parts various part of repo. So it has to be unique.
For css it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter it applies stying if you ask by #id_name or .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IPv4 Link Local</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/tils/ipv4-link-local/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 09:24:33 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/tils/ipv4-link-local/</guid>
      <description>To participate in wide-area IP networking, a host needs to be configured with IP addresses for its interfaces, either manually by the user or automatically from a source on the network such as a Dynamic Host Configuration Protocol (DHCP) server. Unfortunately, such address configuration information may not always be available. It is therefore beneficial for a host to be able to depend on a useful subset of IP networking functions even when no address configuration is available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KISS</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/tils/kiss/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 19:18:04 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/tils/kiss/</guid>
      <description>KISS is an acronym for &amp;ldquo;Keep it simple stupid&amp;rdquo; (notice no comma).
Stupid does not refer to the user. To quote Wikipedia:
 The principle is best exemplified by the story of Johnson handing a team of design engineers a handful of tools, with the challenge that the jet aircraft they were designing must be repairable by
an average mechanic in the field under combat conditions with only these tools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Change Orientation of an Image</title>
      <link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/tils/change-orientation-of-an-image/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 17:30:23 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/tils/change-orientation-of-an-image/</guid>
      <description>A single-line CSS transform is all it takes to change the orientation of an image (or any DOM element, really).
For instance, if I have an image that is on its side, I can use the following rotate transform to orient it correctly.
1 2 3  img { transform: rotate(90deg); }   Testing you babay
1 2  import os os.path.join()    Go hello world
1 2 3 4 5 6 7  import ( &amp;#34;fmt&amp;#34; ) func main() { fmt.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>