<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on knowledge base</title><link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/category/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on knowledge base</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 14:45:34 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kbs.murarisumit.in/category/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Stock Market Fundamentals</title><link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/en/e512411ab8eae0a9d1f2c776df249b21/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 14:45:34 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/en/e512411ab8eae0a9d1f2c776df249b21/</guid><description>&lt;p>Basic terms and concepts in the stock market:&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="shares-">Shares :&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Certificates or book entries representing ownership in a corporation or similar entity.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="parface-value-">Par/Face Value :&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Usually important for debt/bonds, because interest is calculated on based of this face value
Decided when releasing the stocks
Par value is usually very low in stocks, because company doesn’t want to have liability if stock prices go down below the par value
It has no connection to the market value of the share of stock&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="outstanding-stocks-">Outstanding stocks :&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Stocks held by shareholders
Publicly traded companies are obligated to report the number of issued and outstanding shares,&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="treasury-stock-">Treasury stock :&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Treasury stock (treasury shares) are the portion of shares that a company keeps in its own treasury
Treasury stock may have come from a repurchase or buyback from shareholders, or it may have never been issued to the public in the first place
Treasury stock is not considered when calculating dividends or earnings per share.
These are kept in the company’s treasury to be used to create extra cash if it is needed. Another reason may be to keep a controlling interest within the treasury to help ward off hostile takeovers.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="share-capital-">Share capital :&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>It consists of all funds raised by a company in exchange for shares of their stocks.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="outstanding-share-capital-">Outstanding share capital :&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Share capital less the par value of shares that are held as the company’s treasury stock.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="earnings-per-shareeps-">Earnings per share(EPS) :&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>A company’s profit divided by its number of common outstanding shares. If a company earning ₹200 in one year had 200 common shares of stock outstanding, its EPS would be ₹1 per share.
The one-year (historical or trailing) EPS growth rate is calculated as the percentage change in earnings per share(EPS).&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="references">References:&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.nasdaq.com/investing/glossary/">http://www.nasdaq.com/investing/glossary/&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.investopedia.com/terms/t/treasurystock.asp">http://www.investopedia.com/terms/t/treasurystock.asp&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.nasdaq.com/investing/glossary/e/earnings-per-share">http://www.nasdaq.com/investing/glossary/e/earnings-per-share&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.investopedia.com/ask/answers/106.asp">http://www.investopedia.com/ask/answers/106.asp&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.investopedia.com/terms/s/sharecapital.asp">http://www.investopedia.com/terms/s/sharecapital.asp&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.investopedia.com/ask/answers/051115/what-difference-between-par-and-no-par-value-stock.asp">http://www.investopedia.com/ask/answers/051115/what-difference-between-par-and-no-par-value-stock.asp&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Mass vs matter ?</title><link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/en/4710840f1b6de62e27bbf0bf75af303e/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 23:46:01 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/en/4710840f1b6de62e27bbf0bf75af303e/</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="mass-vs-matter-">Mass vs matter ?&lt;/h4>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Mass is a measure of an object&amp;rsquo;s inertia and is quantified in terms of kilograms or grams, while matter refers to anything that occupies space and has mass.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Matter is all the “stuff” that exists in the universe. It has both mass and volume. Mass measures the amount of matter in a substance or an object. The basic SI unit for mass is the kilogram (kg).11&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Matter is anything that occupies space (having volume) and has mass is used to measure the amount of matter in a substance or an object.&amp;quot;&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Still confused, what is &amp;ldquo;mass&amp;rdquo; and what is &amp;ldquo;matter&amp;rdquo; ?&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>Bit more detailed explanation:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Mass&lt;/strong>: If we have a weight of 70kg. This is the amount of matter in the us. It is the same whether we are on Earth, the Moon, or in space.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Matter&lt;/strong>: We are made of matter. We have mass &amp;amp; we occupy space. We are made of cells, tissues, and organs. These are all made of atoms and molecules. The rabbit is made of matter.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h4 id="what-is-weight-then-">What is weight then ?&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Do we have a weight or mass of 70kg ?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We need to know &amp;ldquo;kg&amp;rdquo; is the unit of mass, not the weight. But we say we have a weight of 70 kg. Why ?
Also the weighing machine shows 70 kg. Why ?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To understand weight, we need to understand gravity.&lt;/p>
&lt;details
>
&lt;summary>
What is gravity
&lt;/summary>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>We have seen whenever we throw some object, after it loses the energy we gave it. It gets acceleration towards the earth as if earth is pulling it towards itself.
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>This acceleration is 9.8 m/s^2 on earth, 1.6 m/s^2 on the moon, 3.7 m/s^2 on Mars etc.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>This acceleration is 0 m/s^2 in space.
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>So, if we throw some object in space, it will keep moving in the same direction. It will not come back to us.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Newton had his theory why we feel this acceleration. He said that mass attracts mass.
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Hence earth attracts us. So, we feel a force that pulls us towards the earth. This force is called gravity.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Einstein had his theory on how this force comes. He said that mass bends the space-time around it. So, objects are pulled towards the mass. This bending of space-time is called gravity.
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>So here even the particle with no mass is pulled towards the mass. Because mass bends the space-time around it.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Whatever the theory of origin of this force, we found that earth &amp;amp; other planets pull objects towards themselves which causes acceleration. This acceleration is called gravity.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/details>
&lt;p>So weight is what we feel because of gravity. Because some acceleration is acting on us. How that acceleration comes is different &amp;amp; everyone has their own theory.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Weight is &lt;code>kg * meter/second^2&lt;/code>. It is measured in Newtons.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="why-do-we-see-our-weight-at-70kg">Why do we see our weight at 70kg&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>On earth our weighing machines are calibrated to show our weight in kg. But it is actually showing our mass in kg. This is because the standard gravitational acceleration on Earth is assumed, and weighing machines are calibrated to show &amp;ldquo;weight&amp;rdquo; in kilograms, which is a bit of a misnomer because kilograms technically measure mass, not weight&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If we took an earth calibration weighing machine to the moon, it would show our weight much less than 70 kg. But our mass would still be 70 kg. Because the weighing machine is calibrated to show weight on earth. If someone calibrated it to show weight on the moon, it would show 70 kg.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ublock Origin Youtube Filter List</title><link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/6e225c364f36afa1b5766490db9e7229/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 14:43:52 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/6e225c364f36afa1b5766490db9e7229/</guid><description>&lt;p>So idea here is to reduce the distraction. One thought that was difficult for me to overcame was&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I should have self-control, no such controls are needed.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Have less distraction and making bad habits(imo) difficult is powerful way to stay more focussed in case I drift.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>It primarily removes&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Videos on Home page.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Suggested videos.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Comments (Wasted time reading it, and endup think, why in this world did I read them).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="steps">Steps&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Go to filters pane: &lt;a href="https://github.com/gorhill/uBlock/wiki/Dashboard:-My-filters">https://github.com/gorhill/uBlock/wiki/Dashboard:-My-filters&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Add content to filters from&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;div class="chroma">
&lt;table class="lntable">&lt;tr>&lt;td class="lntd">
&lt;pre tabindex="0" class="chroma">&lt;code>&lt;span class="lnt">1
&lt;/span>&lt;span class="lnt">2
&lt;/span>&lt;span class="lnt">3
&lt;/span>&lt;span class="lnt">4
&lt;/span>&lt;span class="lnt">5
&lt;/span>&lt;span class="lnt">6
&lt;/span>&lt;span class="lnt">7
&lt;/span>&lt;span class="lnt">8
&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/td>
&lt;td class="lntd">
&lt;pre tabindex="0" class="chroma">&lt;code class="language-fallback" data-lang="fallback">&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">!Home page all videos page
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">youtube.com##ytd-browse.ytd-page-manager.style-scope
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">!Suggestion by youtube
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">youtube.com###related
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">!Removes comments
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;span class="line">&lt;span class="cl">##.ytd-comments.style-scope
&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/td>&lt;/tr>&lt;/table>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Batman vs Superman Martha Flaw</title><link>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/posts/batman-vs-superman-martha-flaw/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 01:05:26 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://kbs.murarisumit.in/posts/batman-vs-superman-martha-flaw/</guid><description>&lt;p>After watch man of steel, which was good. It would nice to see how krypton got destroyed and General Zod&amp;rsquo;s past.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Went on to see batman vs superman, at first I thought title was stupid. Batman vs superman makes no sense, but yeah it&amp;rsquo;s justifies after you watch movie, but some creativity here would have been nice, from someone whose company thrives on creativity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I personally like spoilers, because would love to see story is being portrayed and only see portrayal if story is good.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="spoilers-ahead">Spoilers Ahead&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Alternate theory for batman vs superman &amp;lsquo;martha&amp;rsquo; moment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Came across below alternate scene from a guy in Quora, reference for the original post: &lt;a href="https://qr.ae/pGw69M">https://qr.ae/pGw69M&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>We're supposed to believe that Wayne has a soft spot and that Superman found it. After finding it, the fortuitous arrival of Lois Lane made him stop and think. Before that point in time, Superman was a false-god and one that with no apparent connection to humanity other than an apparent need to act godly and save people. He was an alien. But then, suddenly, this man had an Earth mother who loved him and raised him. Bruce didn't know that. We're supposed to fill in the blanks. It was a bad job.
Instead of introducing us to Bruce Wayne's back-story for the 58,000th time (in the beginning), those precious 5 minutes should have been spent evolving why Batman spared Superman's life. It could have also coincided with a &amp;quot;nuke blast&amp;quot; from Doomsday.
Superman says, &amp;quot;Martha&amp;quot;.
Batman pauses. Garbles about his mom.
Lois arrives.
A dialogue ensues with Batman ordering Lois to get out of the way. She covers Superman with her body.
Batman doesn't want to kill Lois. She won't let go. It is just enough time for her to talk.
She explains that Superman isn't a god. He's a &amp;quot;human&amp;quot;, raised on Earth by two human parents who adopted him as an infant. She begins to tell him that his father raised him to serve mankind and that his mother is alive.
Superman gains a bit of strength and says, &amp;quot;Not for long. My mother, Martha Kent is about to die. Lex has her prisoner. He ordered me to kill you to save her life.&amp;quot;
Lois --being coy-- knows Bruce's story. &amp;quot;What would you do to save your mom from being shot by the robber, Bruce?&amp;quot;
Batman is nonplussed.
Superman says, &amp;quot;This is what I tried to tell you Bruce. Before we started fighting. I need to work together with you to save my mom. If you want my life after that, I willingly give it to you. You can keep the spear. I won't refuse. I'm yours, but please help me save my mother.&amp;quot;
Batman says, &amp;quot;A truce then. It looks like we will both need each other then. Lex is working on something terrible in the Kryptonian ship. You go to Lex. I promise you, your mother won't die tonight. I will save her. But you must stop Lex...&amp;quot;
In the battle, Batman realizes who Superman really is. In death, Batman realizes what he almost did -- destroy Humanity. He has a change of heart: Humanity needs the Metahumans. All of them.
That would have been more fluid. It would have taken --maybe-- an extra 120 seconds. The spare 180 seconds taken back from the Bruce Wayne intro in the beginning could have been put into the fight scene. Three minutes is a HUGE amount of time in a fight scene. It could have been even-more-epicker.
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre></description></item></channel></rss>